Orange
字幕组
怦然心动
翻译：Linton 三火子 知了 云菌 KJ肉包 兔子 Supreme
我只希望朱莉 贝克能够离我远点
All i ever wanted was for Juli Baker to leave me alone.
校对：莫愁 达斯  监制：Isabella
一切开始于1957年的夏天
It all began in the summer of 1957,
一年级的暑假
before the start of second grade.
我喜欢这里
I like this place.
真美 我的房间是什么颜色的呀
It's cool. Uh, what color is my room?
后期：橘子  压制：sherlock
一会儿你就知道咯
Just you wait.
咱们进去瞧瞧  嘿 布莱斯 过来
Let's see what's inside. Hey, come on, buddy Bryce.
咱父子俩把车上的东西搬下来吧
Why don't, uh, you and I go help unload the van...
让姑娘们进去
...and the womenfolk here can get in
收拾一下厨房
the kitchen and start setting up
好的 爸爸
Okay, dad.
对我而言 这意味着我步入了
For me, it was the beginning of what would be...
长达五年的
...more than half a decade of strategic
人际逃避和社交不适的生涯
avoidance and social discomfort.
嗨 我叫朱莉 贝克 - 喂喂喂 你干嘛呢
- hi, i'm Juli Baker. - hey, hey, what are you doing?
你们需要帮忙吗
Don't you want some help?
不必了 里面是些贵重物品
No. there's some valuable things in there.
那这个呢？ - 不用了不用了
- how about this one? - no, no, no.
你还是快些回家吧 你妈妈没准正在找你呢
Why don't you run along home. your mother's probably wondering where you are.
不会的 我妈妈知道我在哪 她没意见的
Oh, no, my mom knows where i am. she said it's fine.
我立刻意识到
It didn't take long to realize
这女孩太不识趣了
this girl could not take a hint.
我们三个人在这有点挤吧 - 我不介意呀
- it's crowded in here with three people. - i don't mind.
- 一点眼色都没有 - 我们一起搬这个吧
- Of any kind. - you wanna push this one together?
布莱斯 你是不是该去给你妈妈帮忙了
Bryce, isn't it time for you to go help your mother?
啊 没错
Oh, yeah.
我真拿她没辙
I mean, nothing would stop her.
我正想朝她发火时
I was about to tell her to get lost
奇怪的事情发生了
when the weird thing happeed.
我简直不敢相信
I couldn't believe it.
我竟然牵了这个奇女子的手
There I was holding hands with this strange girl.
你好呀
Well, hello.
- 看来你已经认识我儿子了 - 是的
- i see you've met my son. - uh-huh.
最后 我祭出了积攒七年的
Finally, i did the only manly thing
所有雄性荷尔蒙
available when you are 7 years old.
然而 我的麻烦还远未结束
However, my troubles were far from over.
当我走进叶尔森老师的教室时
The minute i walked into Miss Yelson's classroom...
布莱斯 你也在这儿啊
Bryce? you're here.
显然 学校并不能让我脱离苦海
It was clear, school would not be a sanctuary.
嘿 布莱斯 你女朋友呢
Hey, Bryce, where's your girlfriend?
我被贴上了各种标签
I was branded for life.
嘿 布莱斯 你为啥不向她求婚呢
Hey, Bryce, why don't you ask her to marry you?
布莱斯和朱莉坐上树梢
Bryce and Juli sitting in a tree
亲亲抱抱举高高
K-I-S-S-I-n-G
我搬来镇上的第一年简直就是一场灾难
My first year in town was a disaster.
瞧
Look at them.
接下来的三年也是差强人意
And the next three weren't much better.
到了六年级 我决定做些什么
But finally, in the sixth grade, i took action.
于是我想出了一个计划
I hatched the plan.
雪莉
Sherry.
雪莉 等等我
Sherry, wait up.
嗨 布莱斯
Hi, Bryce. heh.
我决定追求雪莉 斯道尔
I asked out Sherry Stalls.
我想问问你愿不愿意
I was wondering if you wanted to go...
这一招的绝妙之处在于
To full appreciate the brilliance of this plan...
朱莉简直恨死了雪莉 斯道尔
...you have to understand that Juli hated Sherry Stalls...
尽管我不知道个中缘由
...though i never understood why.
雪莉貌美心善 秀发飘飘
Sherry was nice, friendly and she had a lot of hair.
一开始我妈一直不肯让我打耳洞
At first, my mother wouldn't let me
但我一直求她
get my ears pierceed but I beg...
我原计划和雪莉吃吃饭
The idea was that Sherry would eat with me...
可能再散散步
...maybe we'd walk around together,
然后朱莉就会对我失去兴趣
and hopefully Juli would lose interest.
但我16岁之前还是不能打耳洞
But i still can't get the hoops till i'm 16.
太可惜了
Oh, that's a shame.
米兰妮也想打耳洞
So melanie wanted to get her ears pierced,
但她妈坚决不同意
but of course her mother said no.
于是她就一怒之下
So she threw a fit and smashed her
把约翰尼 马蒂斯的精选辑给砸了
Johnny Mathis Greatest Hits albim
然后她就被禁足了
...and she got grounded, so now she can't
连我的睡衣派对都来不了
come to my pajamaat sleepover party.
事情进展的不错
Things were unfolding quite nicely.
你的科学实验准备怎么做
What are you doing for your science project?
直到我所谓的挚友 加利特埃恩德
That is, until my supposed best friend, Garrett Einbinder...
打起了雪莉的主意
...took an interest in Sherry himself.
我想展示护发素
I was thinking of showing how split ends
是如何修复头发分叉的
react with different being poisoned?
这主意真棒
That's fascinating.
加利特这个重色轻友的叛徒
Loyalty gave way to desire and garrett, the turncoat...
告诉了雪莉 我接近她的目的
...told Sherry what i was up to.
混蛋
Jerk.
她很生气
She didn't take it well.
至于朱莉 她很快
Word got back to Juli, and pretty soon she
又开始视奸我
started up with the the google eyes again?
但这次她更过分了
Only this time it was worse.
她开始嗅我的味道
She started sniffing me.
没错 嗅
That's right, sniffing me.
这是在搞什么
What was that all about?
我唯一的期盼便是来年的毕业
My only consolation was that next year would be different.
等我上了初中
Junior high, bigger school.
或许我们就不会在一个班了
Maybe we'd be in different classes and
到时一切都将结束
it would finally,finally be over
见到布莱斯 洛斯基的第一眼 我便心动了
The first day i met Bryce Loski, i flipped.
他的眼眸让我深陷其中
It was those eyes, something in those dazzling eyes.
我们一起搬吧
You wanna push this one together?
当时他家刚搬到我家隔壁
His family had just moved into the neighborhood...
我过去帮他们搬东西
...and i'd gone over to help them.
我才在卡车里待了两分钟
I'd been in the van all of two minutes
他爸爸就让他去帮他妈妈
when his dad sent him off to help his mther
我看得出来他并不想去
I could see he didn't wanna go.
所以我追了上去
So i chased after him to see if we could
想问问他进屋前能不能先玩一会儿
play a little before he got trapped inside
下一刻 我便意识到他正牵着我的手
The next thing i know, he's holding my hand...
凝视着我
...and looking right into my eyes.
我的心停止了跳动
My heart stopped.
这一刻到来了吗
Was this it?
我要献出初吻了吗
Would this be my first kiss?
- 可没想到他妈妈出来了 - 你好呀
- but then his mother came out. - well, hello.
他一下子尴尬了 瞬间羞红了脸
And he was so embarrassed, his cheeks turned completely red.
那晚上 我辗转反侧
I went to bed that night thinking
不停幻想着初吻的场景
of the kiss that might have been.
我知道他对我动心了
I mean, it was clear he had feelings for me,
只是羞于启齿
but he was just too shy to show them
妈妈说过男孩子都是这样的
My mother said boys were like that.
- 于是我决定帮助他 - 布莱斯 你也在这里啊
- so i decided to help him out. - Bryce? you're here.
我会尽全力
I would give him plenty of
帮他克服羞怯
opportunity to get over his shyness
到了六年级 我学着收敛些许
By the sixth grade, i'd learned to control myself.
却没想到半路杀出个雪莉 斯道尔
Then Sherry Stalls entered the picture.
她不过是个
Sherry Stalls was nothing but a whiny,
多嘴的腹黑小人而已
gossipy, backsstabbing flirt.
头发长见识短
All hair and no substance.
而且他竟然
And there she was...
和布莱斯牵着手 那可是我家布莱斯
...holding hands with Bryce. my Bryce.
那是我要贡献初吻的人啊
The one who was walking around with my first kiss.
我决定忽略她
My solution was to ignore her.
我知道布莱斯的性格
I knew a boy of Bryce's caliber.
总有一天能意识到
...would eventually see through a
雪莉 斯道尔有多浅薄无知
shallow conniver like Sherry Stalls.
只过了一周 他们果然分手了
It took all of a week. they broke up at recess.
看得出她很生气
She didn't take it well.
自从布莱斯脱离了雪莉的魔掌
Now that Bryce was out of Sherry's evil
他开始对我友善起来
clutches, he started being nice to me
- 嗨 朱莉 - 嗨 布莱斯
- hi, Juli. - hi, Bryce.
他是如此腼腆可人
He was so shy and so cute...
就连他的头发都散发着西瓜的清香
...and his hair, it smelled like watermelon.
我简直如痴如醉
I couldn't get enough of it.
一年来 我都在偷偷地闻着他的发丝
I spent the whole year secretly sniffing watermelon...
期盼着何时能送走我的初吻
...and wondering if i was ever going to get my kiss.
升入七年级后 生活变了样
Seventh grade brought changes, all right.
但最大的变化并非发生在学校
But the biggest one didn't happen at school.
而是在家中
It happened at home.
外公搬来与我们同住
My grandfather came to live with us.
妈妈说 他如此凝望 只因心念外婆
Mom said he stared like that because he missed grandma.
那不是外公会
That was not something grandpa
跟我聊起来的事
would ever talk about with me
事实上 我们几乎
As a matter of fact, he never talked
从未有过交流
about much of anything with me
直到那天 朱莉的名字登上了报纸
That is, until Juli appeared in the local newspaper.
- 布莱斯 可以和你聊聊吗 - 怎么了
- oh, Bryce. may i speak with you? - what?
坐吧 孩子
Have a seat, son.
跟我讲讲你朋友朱莉贝克吧
Tell me about your friend Juli Baker.
其实朱莉算不上我朋友
Juli. she's not exactly my friend.
为什么
Oh. why's that?
您为什么这么好奇
Why do you wanna know?
朱莉贝克登上报纸
Now, Juli Baker did not wind up in the mayfield times...
可不是因为她天赋异禀
...for being an eighth-grade einstein.
本地女孩赖在树上
而是因为她赖在无花果树上
No, she got front-page coverage because she
死活不肯下来
refused to climb out of a sycamore tree
朱莉贝克和那棵无花果树
Juli Baker and that stupid sycamore tree.
她总觉得那棵树是上帝的恩赐
She always thought it was god's gift
使我们这个小地方也能熠熠生辉
to our little corner of the universe
嗨 布莱斯 要不要过来
Hey, Bryce. wanna come climb the
我们一起爬树呀 很好玩的
tree with me and my brothers. it's fun
不了 谢谢
No, thanks.
布莱斯 来吧 很好玩的 你能看到所有的东西呢
Bryce. come up here. it's fun. You can see everything.
我没时间
I can't.
我爸叫我帮他修
My dad needs me to help him fix...
修个东西
...a thing.
拉倒吧
That's all i needed.
让我和朱莉贝克一起爬树
Climb up a tree with Juli Baker.
我马上就掉回二年级的噩梦里去
I'd be dragged right back into the second grade.
布莱斯和朱莉爬上树梢
Bryce and Juli sitting in a tree.
还不如让我下半辈子吃青豆度日呢
Why don't you just make me eat lima beans for the rest of me life.
还有三个街区
It's three blocks away.
两个街区
Two blocks.
一个
One block away.
搞得好像多了不起似的
like that's valuable information.
明明很惹人厌
- I hate it when she does that
我还想着
I like to think there's at least
万一校车不会来呢
a chance the bus won't show
这棵树在晨曦中尤为美丽 你觉得呢
I think the tree looks particularly beautiful in this light,don't you
如果你的美丽指的是极其丑陋的话
If by "beautiful" you mean "unbelievably
没错 它很美丽
ugly," then, yesa painting of it
你眼神不好吧 我真同情你
You're just visually challenged. i feel sorry for you.
眼神不好
"visually challenged"?
这竟然是出自
This from the girl who lived in a house
自家房子是邻里笑料的人之口
that was the joke of the neighborhood
窗前爬满灌木
They had bushes growing over windows
门前杂草丛生
and weeds all over the place
我爸爸都为此不爽
It bugged my dad bigtime.
噢 看呀
Oh, there he is.
一个自以为是画家的砌墙工
The bricklayer who thinks he's a painter.
那破车都丑成这样了
that truck's not ugly enough in real life
还得画幅画裱起来吗
He's gotta make a painting of it?
他画的美景在集市上可是很抢手的
No, he does landscapes. sells them at the county fair.
人们都觉得画得好
People say they're beautiful.
风景画 我跟你说吧
Landscapes? let me tell you something.
如果他能把他的破院子
The world would have more beauty in it...
美化一点点
...if he'd do a little landscaping on
世界都会因此美丽不少的
that piece of crap he calls a yard
真同情他的妻子 嫁给了一个空想家
I feel bad for his wife. she married a dreamer.
梦想与现实间的冲突
Because of that, one of the two
总得会不那么愉快的
of them will always be unhappy
没错 可为什么还要牵连我们
Yeah, fine. but why do we have to be unhappy?
和她家的脏院子相比
As annoying as the yard was to my dad...
还是树上的朱莉贝克
...it was nothing compared to how
更为恼人
annoying Juli Baker was in that tree
还有三个街区
Three blocks away.
每天早上我们都要忍受
Every morning we had to listen to the sound...
她不厌其烦的预报
...of her blow-by-blow traffic report.
两个街区
Two blocks.
到啦
There you go.
为什么要叫他们三个臭皮匠呢
Why do they call it the three stooges?
- 明明有五个人 - 什么
- i mean, there's five of them. - what?
你看啊 蘑菇头 拉里 胖子 西普和卷毛乔伊
Well, yeah, there's moe, larry, curly, shemp and curly joe.
没错 但每次只有三个人出场
- yeah, but they only have three at a time. - yeah.
你知道吗 我讨厌乔伊
You know, i hate curly joe. i mean,
他根本算不上臭皮匠
he shouldn't even be a stooge
姑娘 我可要报警了
Listen, girl, i'm this close to calling the police.
你这是侵犯私人领地
You are trespassing and obstructing
妨碍施工
progress on a contracted job
怎么了
Guys, what's going on?
要么你自己下来 要么砍树了
Either you come down... or we gonna cut you down.
你们快上来
You guys, come up here with me.
我们都在树上他们就不敢砍的
They won't cut it down if we're all up here.
- 车车车 - 朱莉真是疯了
- Bus, bus, bus. - Juli was frantic.
他们想要砍掉她的树
They wanted to cut down her tree.
我真不明白
I couldn't understand why that
那颗树枝畸形的树为什么对她那么重要
mutant tangle of gnarly branches meant so much to her
- 布莱斯 求你了 - 我同情她
- Bryce, please. - I feel bad for her.
别管她
Leave her.
但我不想因此逃课
But i wasn't about to cut school over it.
快点 老铁
Come on, bro.
你为什么不把她当朋友呢
Why isn't she your friend, Bryce?
等您真正了解她您就明白了
You'd have to know Juli.
我倒真挺想认识她
Well, i'd like to.
为什么
Why?
这姑娘挺有骨气
That girl has an iron backbone.
要不你什么时候请她过来玩吧
Why don't you invite her over sometime?
有骨气
An iron backbone?
她那是顽固
She's just stubborn...
还没有自知之明
...and she's pushy beyond belief.
是吗
Is that so?
她从二年级开始就缠着我
And she's been stalking me since the second grade.
不是每个人都能和这样的女孩子做邻居
Well, a girl like that doesn't live next door to everyone.
他们逃过一劫
Lucky them.
读读这个
Read this.
抛开你的偏见
Without prejudice.
跟我有多想了解她似的
Like i needed to know anything more about Juli Baker.
赖在树上的女孩
朱莉第二天早上不在公交站台
Juli wasn't at the bus stop the next morning.
之后也不在
Or the morning after that.
她去了学校 但不知道怎么去的
She was at school, but you'd never know it.
小不点乔 他脸上妆太浓了
little joe? he's got so much
他又不老
makeup on... - He doesn't age.
我告诉自己我该庆幸
I told myself i should be glad about it.
这不就是我一直盼着的吗
I mean, isn't that what i'd always wanted?
不过我还是为她感到难过
But still, i felt bad for her.
我本来准备去和她道个歉
I was gonna tell her i was sorry,
但是随即我想到 不行 我不能这么干
but then i thought... no, that's the last thing i needed.
朱莉贝克会以为我想念她
Juli Baker thinking i missed her.
我明白你为什么喜欢待这儿
I see why you like to come out here.
你能帮我跟你妈解释一下吗
Would you mind explaining it to your mother?
我喜欢看我爸画画
I loved to watch my father paint.
事实上 我更爱在我爸画画时和他聊天
Or really, i loved to hear him talk while he painted.
这帮助我了解他
I learned a lot about my dad that way.
他什么都跟我说
He told me all sorts of things...
比如他怎么找到的第一份运送干草的工作
...like how he got his first job delivering hay
还有他希望能完成学业
and how he'd wished he'd finished college
有一天他的举动让我出乎意料
Then one day he surprised me.
你和那个布莱斯 洛斯基怎么了
What's going on with you and, uh, Bryce Loski?
什么意思 我们没什么
What do you mean? nothing.
喔 好吧
Oh, okay.
我不该问的
My mistake.
你问这个干什么
Why would you even think that?
没什么
No reason.
只是你
Just that you...
整天讨论他
...talk about him all the time.
我有吗
I do?
是哦
Mm-hm.
我不知道
I don't know.
我猜是因为他的眼睛
I guess it's something about his eyes.
或者他的笑容
Or maybe his smile.
那他这个人怎么样
But what about him?
- 什么 - 你需要看整体
- what? - you have to look at the whole landscape.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
一幅画的整体效果远比细节重要
A painting is more than the sum of its parts.
一头牛只是一头牛
A cow by itself is just a cow.
一片草地本身只是长满了花和草
A meadow by itself is just grass, flowers.
穿过树丛的阳光
And the sun peeking through the
仅仅只是一束光线
trees is just a beam of light.
但是当你把他们组合在一起
But you put them all together...
它可以变成奇迹
...and it can be magic.
我不是很理解他的话
I didn't really understand what he
直到有一天下午
was saying until one afternoon..
我爬上无花果树
...when i was up in the sycamore tree.
准备去解一只风筝
I was rescuing a kite.
那太高了 我从没爬这么高过
It was a long way up, higher than i'd ever been.
我爬得越高 越是被眼前的风景震撼到
And the higher i got, the more amazed i was by the view.
我享受微风中奇妙的芬芳
I began to notice how wonderful the breeze smelled.
就像阳光和野草
Like sunshine and wild grass.
我不断大口呼吸着
I couldn't stop breathing it in...
让这些陌生而甜美的气息充斥我的肺
...filling my lungs with the sweetest smell i'd ever known.
嘿 你找到我的风筝了
Hey, you found my kite.
布莱斯 你该上来瞧瞧
Bryce, you should come up here.
这儿太美了
It's so beautiful.
我不能 我扭伤了我的 呃
I can't. i sprained my, um...
我得了皮疹
I have a rash.
从那刻开始 那里成了我的基地
From that moment on, that became my spot.
我可以长时间坐在这儿 只为了观察这个世界
I could sit there for hours, just looking out at the world.
有时候落日会呈现出粉紫色
Some days the sunsets would be purple and pink.
有时候会是耀眼的橙色
And some days they were a blazing orange...
染上整片天际的云彩
...setting fire to the clouds on the horizon.
有天在欣赏这迷人的落日时
It was during one of those sunsets that my father's idea...
我突然理解了爸爸说的
...of the whole being greater than the sum of its parts...
整体胜过局部的概念
...moved from my head to my heart.
有时候我会起个大早
Some days i would get there extra
去看日出
early to watch the sunrise
有一天早上 当我正在打着腹稿
One morning i was making mental notes...
想着怎么向我爸爸描绘
...of how the streaks of light
丝丝缕缕的光线
were cutting through the clouds
穿透云层的景象
...so i could tell my dad...
我听到底下一阵嘈杂
...when i heard a noise below.
不好意思
Excuse me.
不好意思 你们不能
Excuse me. i'm sorry, but you can't
把车停这儿 这是公交站台
park there. That's a bus stop.
嘿 你在上面干什么
Hey, what are you doing up there?
你得下来 我们需要把这大家伙砍下来
You can't be up there, we're gonna take this thing down.
- 这棵树 - 是的 现在赶紧下来
- the tree? - yeah. now come on down.
- 谁允许你们砍树的 - 这儿的主人
- but who told you, you could cut it down? - the owner.
为什么
Why?
他准备在这里盖房子 这棵树妨碍了他
He's gonna build a house, and this tree's in the way.
所以快下来吧姑娘 我们要开工了
so come on, girl, we got work to do.
你们不能砍了它 就是不能
you can't cut it. You just can't.
听着女孩 你再这样我要报警了
Listen, girl. i'm this close to calling the police.
你这是擅自入侵私人空间
You are trespassing and obstructing
和妨碍正常作业
progress on a contract job
现在你要么下来 要么我们就直接砍了
Now either you come down, or we're gonna cut you down.
砍吧 连我一起砍下来好了
Go ahead. cut me down.
我是不会下来的 我永远不下来
I'm not coming down. i'm never coming down.
布莱斯 你们快上来和我一起
Bryce. you guys, come up here with me.
如果我们都在上面他们就不会砍树了
They won't cut it down if we're all up here.
布莱斯求求你 别让他们砍树好吗
Bryce, please don't let them do this.
求你们了
Come on, you guys.
布莱斯 求你了 你不用爬
Bryce, please. you don't have to come
这么高 就上来一点点就好
up this high. just a little way.
布莱斯 求你了 求你
Bryce, please. please.
接下来发生的事都很模糊
What happened after that was a blur.
看上去整个镇上的人都来了
It seemed like the whole town was there.
但我始终不肯动
But still i wouldn't move.
然后我爸爸出现了
Then my father showed up.
他和消防员商量让他搭着救生梯爬到了我这儿
He talked a fireman into letting him come up to where i was.
宝贝 是时候该下去了
Sweetie, it's time to come down.
爸爸 求你别让他们砍树
Daddy, please don't let them do this.
- 宝贝儿 - 爸爸 你看
- sweetie... - daddy, look.
在这里可以看到一切 你可以
You can see everything. you can
从这儿看到整个世界
see the whole world from here.
没有什么风景比我女儿的安全更重要 现在 下来吧
No view is worth my daughter's safety. now, come on.
我不要
I can't.
朱莉安娜 现在跟我下来
Julianna, it's time to come down now.
求你了 爸爸
Please, daddy.
听话
It's time.
就这样结束了
And that was it.
我起码痛哭了两个礼拜
I must've cried for two weeks straight.
当然 我还是在上学并且尽我所能认真学习
Oh, sure, i went to school and did the best i could...
但是我失去了支柱
...but nothing seemed to matter.
- 朱莉 - 啊
- Juli? - huh?
你知道答案吗
Do you know the answer?
呃 伯罗奔尼撒战争
Uh, the peloponnesian war?
我确信这是某个问题的答案
I'm sure that's the answer to something...
但我问的是平行四边形的面积
...but i was looking for the area of a rhomboid.
不知道为什么 平行四边形和等腰直角三角形
Somehow, rhomboids and isosceles right triangles...
对我来说都不重要
...didn't seem so important.
我开始骑自行车上学 为了避免经过树桩
I rode my bike so i wouldn't have to pass by the stump...
对我来说那曾经是一棵世界上
...that used to be the earth's
最伟大的无花果树
most magnificent sycamore tree.
但是不管我怎么避开它 我还是忍不住想到它
But no matter what i did, i couldn't stop thinking about it.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
那只是一棵树
It was just a tree.
不 那不仅仅是一棵树
No, it wasn't just a tree.
我不希望你忘记
I never want you to forget how
这棵树带给你的奇妙感受
you felt when you were up there.
谢谢你 爸爸
Thanks, dad.
这是我每天睁开眼睛见到的第一个画面
It was the first thing i saw every morning...
也是我闭上眼睛前见到的最后一个画面
...and the last thing i saw before i went to sleep.
直到有一天我不会对着它流泪
And once i could look at it without crying...
我领悟到了比树和发生过的事
...i saw more than the tree and
更多的东西
what being up there meant to me.
我发现我观察周围
I saw the day that my view of
事情的角度开始改变了
things around me started changing.
我思考着 我是否
And i wondered, did i still feel
还对布莱斯抱有感情
the same thing about Bryce?
我对鸡蛋不是特别感兴趣
I've never been a huge fan of eggs.
我的意思是 吃不吃鸡蛋我都无所谓
I mean, i could always just take them or leave them.
直到有一天 在斯凯勒布朗家的车库里
That is, until one day in skyler brown's garage...
我对鸡蛋开始打心底感到厌恶
...when my feelings about eggs were solidified.
嘿 嘿嘿 伙计们 埃德娜决定好她的早餐了
Hey, hey, hey. guys. Edna's found her breakfast.
要我说 如果黏滑的爬行动物觉得蛋合胃口
I mean, if a slimy reptile found them appetizing...
那么它绝对不会再出现在我的食用菜单里
...there was certainly no place for them in my diet.
哥们 这太酷了
Oh, man, that's so cool.
她甚至不用咀嚼
She doesn't even have to chew. i mean,
想想这省了多少时间
think of all the time you'd save.
要不是我姐姐丽奈特
I could've gone my whole life not
我这辈子都不用看到
knowing that snakes eat eggs raw.
蛇生吞蛋这种戏码
...if it hadn't been for lynetta.
她和斯凯勒布朗要商量关于联赛的事情
She had a major-league thing for skyler brown.
这太野蛮了
I think it's gross.
他和朱莉的哥哥 马特马克 组成了一个乐队
He and Juli's brothers, matt and mark, had formed a band.
丽奈特会看他们表演
And lynetta would watch them practice.
真高明
That is so neat.
你觉得呢 布莱斯
How about that, huh, Bryce?
是啊 高明
Yeah. neat.
布莱斯 你猜他该怎么消化
So, Bryce, how do you think he's gonna digest that?
- 胃酸 - 没这么简单
- stomach acid? - you'd like to think that.
等着 大家安静 好戏开始了
Wait, everybody quiet. here he goes.
轻松解决
Eggs over easy.
恶心 恶心 恶心 太恶心了
Gross. gross, gross, gross.
等等 你还没看到最精彩的部分
Wait, wait. you haven't seen the best part.
呕
Ugh!
想吐
Gross.
我试图装作毫不在意 但并不起效
I tried to be casual about it, but it didn't take.
Orange
字幕组
我开始做噩梦
I started having bad dreams.
我被困在了一个大鸡蛋里
I'd be trapped inside a huge egg...
怪物会张大
...and this monster would open
他的嘴并开始吞食我
his jaws and start to devour me.
我每次都及时醒过来
I'd wake up just in time.
但是很快真正的噩梦出现了
Then the real nightmare began.
嗨 布莱斯 我给你们家带来了这个
Hi, Bryce. i brought these over for you and your family.
- 我的鸡开始下蛋了 - 什么
- my chickens are laying eggs. - what?
你记得艾比 邦妮 克莱德
You remember Abby and Bonnie and Clyde
德克斯特 尤妮斯和弗洛伦斯吗
and Dexter and Eunice and Florence?
那些我在科技展览会上孵化的小鸡
the ones i hatched for the science fair.
当然记得
How could I forget?
那真是典型的朱莉贝克式事迹
It was classic Juli Baker.
她完全成了整个展览会的焦点
She totally dominated the fair.
就因为她的实验是
And get this, her project was all
观察无聊的小鸡出壳
about watching boring eggs hatch
我可是准备了火山爆发的现场模拟
I mean, here i had a live-action erupting volcano...
但是所有人在意的都是朱莉的无聊透顶的鸡
...and all anyone cared about was Juli's boring chicks...
挣破它们无趣的壳
...breaking out of their boring shells.
欧 我觉得最后一只也要出壳了
Oh, i think the last one's hatching.
是的 它正在孵化
Oh, it's hatching.
孩子们 到这儿来
Kids, come over here.
好吧 她赢了 我输了
But hey, she won. i lost.
我被彻底无视了
I've never been one to dwell.
它出来了
Here it comes.
但是这并不意味着我得吃她可恶的鸡蛋
But that didn't mean i had to eat her lousy eggs.
我觉得朱莉送我们这些鸡蛋真是太贴心了
I think it was very sweet of Juli to bring us those eggs.
不关我的事 我明天还是要吃麦片
I don't care. i'm still having cereal tomorrow.
我们怎么确定这些蛋里就没有雏鸡呢
Yeah, how do we know there's no chicks in one of those eggs?
我小时候常常吃新鲜的鸡蛋
I used to eat farm-fresh eggs when
它们很美味
i was a kid. They were delicious.
当然 它们当然好吃
Yeah, well, that's all well and good...
但是万一我们敲开一颗蛋发现里面有小鸡尸体滑出来呢
...but what if we crack one open and a dead chick falls out?
他们养公鸡了吗 如果没有
Do they have a rooster? if they don't
那么鸡蛋是不会受精的
have a rooster the eggs can't be fertile.
而如果他们养了公鸡 我们会知道的
And if they had a rooster, we'd know.
公鸡叫声所有邻居都能听到
the whole neighborhood would know.
也许他们给公鸡做了变声
Maybe they got it de-yodeled.
变什么
"de-yodeled"?
就是 处理了一下公鸡
You know. de-cock-a-doodle-doo'd.
你在说什么乱七八糟的
What the hell are you talking about?
就像弄哑狗狗
Like they de-bark dogs.
布莱斯 你为什么不直接问问朱莉呢
Bryce, why don't you just ask Juli?
什么
What?
你不敢跟她说话
you afraid to talk to her?
我没有不敢跟她说话
i'm not afraid to talk to Juli.
是你不敢吧
I know you are, but what am i?
- 好了 只要找她问清楚 - 布莱斯
- okay. just talk to her and find out. - Bryce.
你能分辨出公鸡吗
How do you tell if one's a rooster?
- 当然 公鸡体型更大 羽毛更长 - 嗯哼
- well, a rooster's bigger. longer feathers. - mm-hm.
它们头上长着红色的鸡冠
They've got that red stuff growing out of their head.
脖子周围也是红色的
and around their neck too.
那应该不难辨认
That shouldn't be too hard to spot.
不过你想
Although, come to think of it,
小鸡也有富有弹性的红色部分
chickens have the rubbery red stuff too.
只是没有那么多
Just not as much.
加勒特对公鸡的专业了解
Garrett's expertise in roosters...
是我们计划避开接触朱莉
...was the cornerstone of our plan
的关键
to avoid contact with Juli Baker.
剩下包括躲在她家的后院围栏外悄悄观察
The balance of which involved spying over her back fence.
- 上这儿来 - 嘘
- come on, come on. - shh. shh.
这边
Over here.
我看不到那些蠢鸡
I can't see the stupid chickens.
我们得让它们离开笼子
We gotta get them out of the coop.
有公鸡吗
Is that a rooster?
不 看起来是小鸡
No, it looks like a chicken.
你怎么分辨的
How can you tell?
跟你说不清楚
It just does.
看到我说的了吧 这就是专家
See what i mean? expertise.
- 嘘 - 怎么了
- shh, shh! - what?
朱莉
Juli.
这里 伙计们
Here, guys.
出来 开饭了
Go on, there you go.
- 这儿 伙计们 - 是的 它们都是小鸡
- here, guys. go on. - yeah, they're all chickens.
- 没有公鸡吗 - 我刚刚怎么说的来着
- There's no rooster? - What did i just say?
你怎么知道的
How can you tell?
- 没有鸡是昂首阔步走的 - 这儿 来啊
- Well,none of them are strutting. - Here,come on.
- 公鸡那么走路吗 - 过来啊
- Roosters strut? - Come on,guys.
- 我刚怎么说的又忘了 - 这儿
- What did I just say? - Here.
而且 它们都没有红色的鸡冠
Plus, hardly any of them have any rubbery red stuff.
- 你们在干什么呢 - 它们绝对都是鸡
- What are you doing? - Yeah. They're definitely all chickens.
他们都是鸡
They're all chickens.
我真为你骄傲 布莱斯
I'm proud of you, Bryce.
- 你战胜了你的恐惧 - 哈
- You overcame your fear. - Huh?
- 你跟她交流过了 - 嗯 是的
- You talked to her. - Oh, heh. yeah.
没什么大不了的
It's no big deal.
她是那么说的吗 都是鸡
That's what she told you? They're all chickens?
没错
Yeah.
她是个天才 你们都是天才
She's a genius. You're both genius
鸡蛋孵出来的当然都是鸡 公鸡的小鸡也是鸡
Of course they're all chickens. A rooster's chicken.
问题是其中一个是公鸡还是全是母鸡啊
The question is one of them a rooster or are they all hens?
母鸡 母鸡怎么了吗
Hens? Who said anything about hens?
然后我猛然想起
Then it hit me.
加勒特对小鸡根本一无所知
Garrett didn't know jack shit about chickens.
- 公鸡都是昂首阔步吗 - 没错
- Do roosters strut? - Yes, they do.
那和这个又有什么关系
What does that have to do with anything?
她们全是母鸡
They're all hens.
好了 鸡蛋没问题才是最主要的
Well, the main thing is the eggs are okay.
别纠结了
It's all settled.
不是对我
Not for me.
我以后绝不可能再吃任何
There was no way i was ever gonna eat anything
和朱莉 贝克有关的东西
that had anything to do with Juli Baker.
- 我不会吃它们的  - 为什么
I'm not eating them.  - Well, why not?
你见过她们的院子吗 它
Have you seen their yard? it's
草都没有 全部是泥巴和鸡屎
There's not even any grass. It's all mud and chicken turds.
哟 真可怕   沙门氏菌
Ew. gross. salmonella.
你认为鸡蛋里可能有沙门氏菌吗
Do you suppose they could have salmonella?
- 不太可能 - 但为什么要冒这个风险呢
- It's not very likely. - Why take the risk?
那这些鸡蛋怎么办
What do we do with the eggs?
还回去
Give them back.
- 还给朱莉吗 - 没错
- Give them back? to Juli? - Sure.
你之前和她说过话 不是吗 那又不会杀了你
You talked to her before, right? It didn't kill you.
嗯 那我要怎么说
Well, what do i say?
告诉她我们不吃鸡蛋
Tell her we don't eat eggs.
额 我们对鸡蛋过敏什么的
Uh, we're allergic to them or something.
加油 动脑子想想啊
Come on, use your brains.
但我总觉得说谎是不好的
It didn't feel right to lie.
而且 就连小学生都知道
Besides, even a seventh grader would know
一家人不可能都对鸡蛋过敏
that entire families aren't allerge to eggs
但我也不想辜负朱莉的好意
But i didn't wanna hurt her feelings either.
所以我就只剩下一个选择
So that left me with only one option.
在我和朱莉 贝克的
And thus another near-death experience
紧张交锋中
in my ongoing saga with Juli Baker
我大多都胜利了
had been succesd most of it.
直到一周后
Until one week later.
嗨 布莱斯 我给你多带了些鸡蛋
Hi, Bryce. Brought you some more eggs.
哇哦
Wow.
- 谢谢 - 你家人喜欢第一盒鸡蛋吗
- Thanks. - Did your family like the first batch?
还用问吗
Do you even have to ask?
太好了 那学校见
Great. See you at school.
我寄希望的一次性事件
What I hoped would be a one-time event
却成了一种生活的开始
was just the beginning of a life
充满着谎言与欺骗
consumed with lies,intrigue and deception
每天早上我都会密切注意着朱莉
Every morning i'd be on the lookout for Juli
这样她来的时候
so if she happened to come, I could
我就能跑去开门
whip the door open for a shut
谢谢
Thanks.
然后在被人发现之前把鸡蛋丢掉
Then I'd dump the eggs before anyone noticed.
怎么会这样 为什么我就是不能面对她
And why? Why couldn't i just face her?
我为什么就是说不出 不用了 谢谢 我们不想要
Why I just can't say "No, thanks. Don't want them.
不需要 喂蛇去吧 这种话
Don't need them.Give them to the snake"?
难道是怕是伤她的心吗
Was i really afraid of hurting her feelings
还是我真的害怕她
or was i just afraid of her?
现在 你要确保你明白了
Now, you wanna make sure you get it...
当布鲁贝克女士第一次建议
When Mrs. brubeck first suggested
我把孵化鸡蛋作为我的研究课题时
hatching eggs as my science project
我并没有多么激动
I was less than excited.
直到我看到了生命中的第一个奇迹
That is, until I saw my first sign of life.
那就是小鸡吗
Is that it?
- 那就是胚胎 - 哇哦
- That's the embryo. - Wow.
- 它看起来像个小豆子 - 确实
- It looks like a bean. - It does.
我们来看看其他的
Let's try the other ones.
忽然我真切地感觉到
Suddenly it felt real.
所有的鸡蛋都是有生命的
All the eggs were alive.
就像 每个鸡蛋里都有个豆宝宝
There were, like, little bean babies inside every one.
在展览会上 六只小鸡都成功孵化了
On the day of the fair, all six chicks hatched.
这个几率多小啊
What are the odds?
今年的一等奖授予朱莉 贝克的课题
This year's top prize goes to Juli Baker for her wonderful project
鸡的诞生
"a chicken is born."
我获得了一等奖
I won first place.
我很开心 不过我真正在意的是
And that was cool, but all I
我的小鸡们
really cared about are my chicks
这边 这边 小家伙们
There you go. there you go, guys.
我妈妈不喜欢我们养鸡
My mom wasn't crazy about us raising chickens.
但是我一直求她
But i begged and pleaded.
我告诉她我能处理一切 我也做到了
I told her i would take care of everything. and i did.
克莱德哪去了
Where's Clyde?
克莱德
Clyde?
嘿 克莱德 怎么回事
Hey, Clyde. What's the matter?
你还好吗 你饿了吗
Are you okay? Aren't you hungry?
过来 怎么了 宝贝
Come on. come here. what's wrong, baby?
来这儿
Come here.
嘿 你不是克莱德了 你是克莱德妈妈了
Hey, you're not clyde. you're clydette.
妈
Mom!
结果是 我的鸡下的蛋我家根本吃不完
As it turned out, my hens laid more eggs than we could eat.
起初我们试着保持
At first we tried to keep up
但经过一个月的煮着吃 煎着吃 烤着吃
but after a month of boiling, frying and deviling...
就像电影运行怪物里一样
like that movie the blob,
我们实在受不了了
We were being overtaken by eggs
斯托比夫人的拜访
Then opportunity in the form of our
给事情带来了转机
neighbor, Mrs. Steuby ,knocked
你好 亲爱的
Hello, dear.
如果你们还有多余的鸡蛋
If you ever have any extra,
我很想买一些
i'd be happy to buy them from  you
- 真的吗 - 当然
- really? - Certainly.
而且我碰巧知道了赫尔姆斯女士
And I happen to know that Mrs.
也有兴趣
Helms would be interested as well
- 太棒了 - 没什么比鲜鸡蛋更好的了
- Great. - Nothing like fresh eggs.
- 谢谢你 斯托比夫人 - 亲爱的客气啦 拜
- Thanks, Mrs. Steuby. - You bet, dear.Bye.
斯托比和赫尔姆斯夫人
Between Mrs. steuby and Mrs. helms,
鸡蛋的问题解决了
My egg overflow problem was solved.
然后我发现洛斯基夫人也该有鸡蛋
Then I realized that Mrs. Loski deserved eggs too.
但是我觉得不该向她收钱
But i didn't think it would be right to charge her.
她是一个非常友善的邻居
She had been such a good neighbor,
当我们东西用完时她会借给我们家
lending us suppliese when we ran out
汽车熄火时还捎带过我妈妈一程
giving my mother a ride when our car wouldn't start.
这是我唯一能做的
It was the least I could do.
除此之外 如果碰巧遇到了布莱斯
Besides, if I happened to run into Bryce,
那就再好不过了
that wouldn't be the end of the world
嗨 布莱斯
Hi, Bryce.
我第三次送鸡蛋去洛斯基夫人家的时候
By the third time I brought eggs over to the Loskis'
我发现布莱斯在等我
I realized Bryce was waiting for me.
等着给我开门 并对我说
Waiting to pull open the door and say,
谢谢 朱莉 学校见
"Thanks, Juli. See you at school.
作为回报 我得到了一些能被布莱斯
And in return, I got a few moments alone
璀璨的目光注视的时光
with the world's most dazzling eyes.
谢谢 朱莉 学校见
Thanks, Juli. See you at school.
真是个好买卖
It was a bargain.
直到有一天
Until the day it wasn't.
那是无花果树被砍的两周后
It was two weeks after the sycamore tree was cut down
我重新开始适应的时候
and I was just starting to feel normal again.
嘿 朱莉 真准时啊
Hey, Juli. Right on schedule.
嗯 风雨无阻
Yeah, well, neither rain nor sleet.
- 啊 - 像邮递员一样
- huh? - you know, the mailman thing?
哦 没错
Oh, right.
所以 你还会坐校车吗
So, um, will you start riding the bus again?
我不知道 那之后我还没去过那儿
I don't know. I haven't been up there since...
看起来没那么糟了 都被清理干净了
It doesn't look so bad anymore. It's all cleared away.
好吧 我得准备去学校了
Well, um, i better get ready for school.
学校见
Guess i'll see you there.
拜拜
See you.
也许布莱斯是对的
Maybe Bryce was right.
也许是时候重新坐校车了
Maybe it was time I started riding the bus again.
毕竟 他不是说他希望我那么做吗
After all, didn't he just tell me he wanted me to?
难道布莱斯 洛斯基想我了
Could it be that Bryce Loski actually misses me?
朱莉 你还在那里干什么
Juli? What are you still doing here?
我在思考
I was just thinking.
今天是垃圾回收日 垃圾车就在前面
It's pickup day. The cans are in front.
知道 要帮忙吗
I know. You need some help?
不用了 我一会儿再丢吧
No. maybe i'll do it later.
那是我的鸡蛋吗
Are those my eggs?
嗯 我扔掉了
Yeah. yeah, i dropped them.
它们没烂啊
They're not broken.
为什么要扔了
Why are you throwing them away?
你不想要吗
Don't you want them?
不是我 我爸认为不应该冒风险
It wasn't me. My dad didn't think it was worth the risk.
风险 什么风险
Risk? what risk?
沙门氏菌
Salmonella.
什么 他担心中毒
What are you talking about? He's afraid of being poisoned?
嗯 朱莉 我是说 看看你家的院子
Well, Juli, i mean, look at your
简直一团糟
back yard. it's completely a mess
它就像铺满了粪便
It's, like, covered in turds.
胡说 我每天都在打扫
That's not true. i clean up after my girls every day.
我们只是不想伤害你的感情
We just didn't wanna hurt your feelings.
所以你一直都把鸡蛋扔掉了是吗
Have you always thrown them away?
知道吗 斯托比太太和赫尔姆斯太太花钱买我的鸡蛋
You know, Mrs. Steuby and Mrs. Helms pay me for my eggs.
- 是吗 - 60美分一打
- they do? - they pay me 60 cents a dozen.
我不知道
I didn't know.
你怎么能这样
How could you?
对不起
I'm sorry.
不 你没有感到惭愧
No, you're not.
很快我就意识到
It didn't take me long to realize
我和朱莉贝克除了旧恨
that i'd traded in my old problems with Juli Baker
又有了新仇
for a whole set of new ones.
她不理我的感觉比
It was actually worse having her mad
她惹我生气时的感觉还要糟
at me than having her annoy me
她的不理不睬一直提醒着我
The way she ignored me was a constant reminder
我曾是个混蛋
that I'd been a jerk.
有一天我在和加勒特打完球
Then one day i was coming home from
回家的路上
playing basketball with Garrett
发现了一件荒唐事
and things got weird.
别害羞 快来 不会弄伤它们的
Don't be so timid. Come on, you won't hurt them.
- 像这样吗 - 没错 就这样
- Like this? - Yeah, that's it.
我的爷爷
My grandfather.
我只见过他穿拖鞋
All I ever saw him wear was slippers.
而现在 他到哪里搞到的工作靴
Now, where did he get those work boots
我不由自主地朝那儿看
I couldn't stop looking over there.
结果越看越生气
And the more i looked, the madder i got.
我的爷爷已经和朱莉聊了超过一个小时
My grandfather had already said more to Juli in one hour...
比他从搬过来和我们一起住
...than he'd said to me in the whole
总共说的话还要多
time he'd been living with us.
我很确定我之前从未见他大笑过
I was pretty sure I'd never seen him laugh.
他和朱莉在干什么
And what was his deal with Juli Baker?
嗨 爷爷
Hi, grandpa.
朱莉和我说了鸡蛋的事
Juli told me about the eggs.
知道吗 布莱斯
You know, Bryce
一个人的性格是在年少时养成的
One's character is set at an early age.
我不想你在歧路上走的太远而无法回头
I'd hate to see you swim out so far you can't swim back.
什么
Sir?
这关乎诚信 孩子
It's about honesty, son.
有时开始的一点不舒服
Sometimes a little discomfort in the beginning...
能够避免一条充满痛苦的道路
can save a whole lot of pain down the road.
当朱莉 贝克生气的样子
When it came to holding a grudge,
真的是令人印象深刻
Juli Baker was truly impressive
整个星期我都想法儿在学校接近她
All week i tried to approach her at school.
她却总能找到办法躲我
She'd always find some way to duck me.
而她在她家的院子里的时候
And whenever she was in her yard,
我爷爷总是和她在一块儿
grandpa was always there with her
终于一个周六 我找到了机会
Finally, one Saturday I saw my opening.
我爷爷去了镇上买药了
My grandfather had gone into town to buy some bengay.
我猜整理院子的工作有点累到他了
I guess the yard work was starting to get to him.
看起来很不错
It's looking real good.
谢谢 大都是切特的功劳
Thanks. Chet did most of it.
我对我的所作所为很抱歉
I'm sorry for what i did.
我只是不明白 你为什么不直接和我说
I just don't get it, Bryce. why didn't you just tell me?
我不知道 当时我犯傻了
I don't know. It was dumb.
我也同样不该评论你家的院子
And i shouldn't have said anything about your yard, either.
那是不对的
It wasn't right.
也不尽然吧
Maybe it's all for the best.
知道吗 我从切特身上学到了很多 太棒了
I mean, look, I learned so much from Chet, it's amazing.
你真幸运
You're lucky.
我甚至都没有爷爷奶奶
I don't even have grandparents anymore.
哦
Oh.
我为他感到难过
I feel sorry for him.
他很想念你的奶奶
He misses your grandma.
你相信吗 他说我使他想起了她
Can you believe it? he says i remind him of her.
- 真的吗 - 我知道 我也这么说
- what? - I know. that's what i said.
他并不是那个意思 他说的是性格方面
But he meant it in a nice way. something about her spirit.
嗯
Yeah.
Well...
我想这些草一定会长得很好
Good luck with the grass. I'm sure it'll come up great.
谢谢
Thanks.
到时候见
I guess i'll see you around.
我想是吧
I guess so.
尽管朱莉 贝克的原谅
While Juli's acceptance of my apology
和我想象中的不太一样
was not all that I hoped for
不过鸡蛋的事总算过去了
at least the eggs thing was finally behind me.
几个月来我终于能享受观看伯南扎牛仔了
The first time in months I could truly enjoy bonanza.
你要去哪儿 怎么打扮成这样
Where you going and why you dressed like that?
斯凯勒家
Skyler's.
马特和马克要录唱片
Matt and Mark are bringing over recording
他们在准备唱片样本的录制
stuff and they're preparing for a demo
样本唱片 说的好像他们知道怎么弄一样
Demo? Like they know how to make a demo.
- 你根本不了解他们
- You don't even know them.
- 没必要 - 我了解那种人
- I don't have to. I know the type
- 你根本什么都不知道 - 别那样对我说话
- You don't know anything. - Don't talk to me like that.
- 我要迟到了 - 11点前回来
- I'm late. - Be back by 11.
好了 一切回归正常
Yep. everything was back to normal.
那女孩儿让你太累了吗
Is that girl working you too hard?
她的名字叫朱莉 还有
That girl's name is Juli. and, no,
她没有那样
she isn't working me too hard
你对她可真是好啊 不是吗
You've developed quite a soft spot for her, huh?
斯蒂文
Steven.
没事 帕蒂 我就是想知道
No, Patsy. Just wanna find out why
你爸爸怎么有精力
your father has the energy
去帮助一个陌生人
to befriend a complete stranger
却没时间陪他的外孙
when he won't throw a baseball
一起打棒球
around with his grandson
- 没事的 爸爸 - 不 有事
- It's okay, dad. - No, it's not okay.
朱莉让爷爷他想起了奶奶
Juli reminds him of grandma.
蕾妮吗 呵
Of Renee? heh.
简直荒唐
That's ridiculous.
你知道为什么贝克一家一直没有修缮他们的院子吗
You know why the Bakers' haven't fixed their yard?
因为他忙着画画吧
Yeah, because he's too busy with his paint-by-numbers kit.
如果你有一个身患严重疾病的兄弟
If you had a brother with a severe handicap
你会怎么做
What would you do
那和这个又有什么关系
What the hell does that have to do with anything?
朱莉的爸爸有一个智力障碍的兄弟
Juli's father has a retarded brother.
那又如何 又不是让他修缮院子
So what? He's not the gardener, is he? heh.
- 斯蒂文 - 哈哈
- Steven. - Ha-ha-ha.
开个玩笑
It was a joke.
知道吗 每家人都有自己的难处
You know, other people have family troubles
他们已经在努力修剪草坪了
and they manage to mow their own lawns.
不知道他们有房子的那种自豪感去哪儿了
I don't know where their pride in ownership is.
那不是他们的房子
They don't own that house.
房东本该负责管理的
The landlord's supposed to maintain it.
贝克先生把所有剩余的钱
Mr. Baker puts every extra penny he
都拿去照顾他的兄弟了
has to caring his brother
出了这种事
Don't they have government
他们不去政府疗养院吗
facilities for that sort of thing
也许他们认为私人疗养院
Maybe they thought that a private
对他兄弟的病情更好吧
facility would be better for him
不管怎样 又不是我们的错
Either way, it's not our fault that their
让他们家染色体有异常的
family has some chromosomal abnormalities
这和染色体一点关系没有
It has nothing to do with chromosomes.
朱莉的叔叔出生时
When Juli's uncle was born, he had the
被脐带缠住了脖子
umbilical cord wrapped neck
如果他有足够的氧气 就会像你儿子一样
If he'd had enough oxygen, he would've been
是一个健康的小宝贝
a perfect little baby just like your son
胡说什么 切特
Goddamn it, chet.
让我静静
Leave me alone!
我感到很抱歉
Sorry about that.
为什么妈妈这么难过
Why is mom so upset?
因为
Because...
如果不是上帝施以恩德
...but for the grace of god...
你妈妈可能就会像贝克夫人一样
...your mother could be standing in mr. Baker's shoes.
她也有个弟弟被脐带绕颈吗
Did her brother have the cord wrapped around his neck too
是你
You did.
幸运的是 给你接生的医生
Luckily, the doctor who delivered you
医术高超 解开了缠绕的脐带
was on the ball and got it untangled
但一切差一点就截然不同了
...but it easily could've gone the other way.
- 想出去散散步吗 - 什么
- wanna go for a walk - huh
有助于理清思绪
I find it helps clear the mind.
如果我真的变成那样 他们会怎么做
What would they have done with me
别去仔细思考一些本可能发生的事 布莱斯
You can't dwell on something that might've been, Bryce.
我爸爸说的那些话 听起来像是
The way my dad was talking, sounds like
他会把我扔进精神病院
he would've thrown me in a nuthouse.
不 不对 这就不公平了
No, no. now, that's not fair.
你不能为一些没发生过的事埋怨他
You can't condemn him for something he hasn't done.
这就是那棵树 对吗
This is where that tree was, wasn't it?
是的
Yeah.
风景一定很美
Must've been a spectacular view.
她是个很好的女孩
She's quite a girl.
有的人黯淡浅薄
Some of us get dipped in flat...
有的人光彩万丈
...some in satin...
有的人败絮藏心
...some in gloss.
而当你无意间邂逅
But every once in a while...
一个灿若虹霓的人
...you find someone who's iridescent.
自此之后
And when you do...
世间只得一个她
...nothing will ever compare.
浅薄 光彩 败絮
Flat, glossy, iridescent?
这些到底是什么意思
What the hell did that mean?
对我来说 朱莉 贝克乏善可陈
Juli Baker had always just seemed plain to me.
直到现在
Until now.
还有当她说起
And the way she talked about what it
坐在那棵树上
felt like to be up in that tree...
置身云端 感受清风拂过时的样子
...to be held above the earth, brushed by the wind.
哪个初中生会像她一样
Who in junior high talks like that?
有种奇怪的感觉
This weird feeling started taking
开始在我内心深处扎根
over in the pit of my stomach
让我很不喜欢
...and i didn't like it.
我失误了
I was slipping, man.
是时候回归正轨了
And it was time to get a grip.
我以前从没为自己的住所感到过困窘
I'd never been embarrassed by where we lived before.
我也没仔细想过和钱有关的事
I also never really thought about money.
我知道我们不富有
I knew we weren't rich, but i didn't
但我也没觉得这有什么大碍
feel like we were missing anything.
直到布莱斯 洛斯基说我家简直是一团乱
That is, until Bryce Loski called our home a complete mess.
敢问芳名
What's your name
玛丽还是苏
Is it mary or sue
敢问芳名
What's your name
我有机会和你在一起吗
Do i stand a chance with you
太难找到一个如此有魅力的人
It's so hard to find a personality
就像我眼中的你
With charms like yours for me
我得做点什么 我也很清楚该做什么
I had to do something and i knew what it was.
敢问芳名
What's your name
- 你们唱得真好听 - 是啊
- oh, you're sounding really good. - yeah.
我们这周末要去斯凯勒家车库录音
We'll record it in skyler's garage this weekend.
很棒的计划啊
That's a wonderful project.
说到计划
Speaking of projects, i was thinking
我觉得修整一下院子应该会很棒
it might be cool to fix up the yard.
- 什么 - 我是说 草种又能花多少钱呢
- what - i mean, how much can grass seed cost?
我能种些草 或者花儿
I could plant a lawn, maybe some flowers.
甚至还能放些篱笆
I could even put up a fence.
宝贝 那是大人该操心的事
Honey, that's a major undertaking.
我可以用卖鸡蛋的钱来支付
I could pay for it with my egg money.
不用 那是你自己的钱
No. That's your money.
房东应该负责这一切
The landlord should be the one taking care of all this.
但他没有 住在这里的是我们
But he doesn't. and we live here.
院子看起来很糟糕
And it looks so bad.
小朱朱
Jules.
怎么了
What's going on?
没事 爸爸
Nothing, dad.
没事的 宝贝
It's okay, sweetheart.
告诉我们
You can tell us.
罗斯基家扔掉了我送的鸡蛋
The Loskis have been throwing away my eggs
他们怕沾染上沙门氏菌
because they're afraid of salmonella.
因为我们家院子一团乱
Because our yard is such a mess.
佩茜这么说了吗
Did patsy say that?
没有 是布莱斯说的
No. Bryce did.
但这一定是他们全家都在说
But it must have been a family discussion.
小男孩自己不会这么想
A boy doesn't come up with that on his own.
- 谁关心他们怎么想 - 对 谁管他们
- who cares what they think - yeah, who cares
- 我关心 - 特瑞娜
- I care. - Trina.
别在意这些
Let's not get into this.
不 我受够了这样的生活 理查德
No, i'm tired of living like this, Richard.
我受够了不得不去做兼职
I'm tired of having to take temp jobs
却只能勉强维持生活
just to make ends meet.
我受够了总得用椅子
I'm tired of having to push a chair
顶住洗衣机
up against the washing machine...
才能把洗衣机门关上
...just to keep the door shut.
我受够了每次自家
I'm tired of having to borrow Mrs.
吸尘器坏了都要去借
Steuby's vacuum cleaner
斯杜比太太家的真空吸尘器
...every time ours breaks down.
你以为这是我想让全家人过上的生活吗
Do you think this is the life i pictured for us
有时为了正确的事 你得做出牺牲
Sometimes you have to sacrifice to do the right thing.
我们最后总是一致认为 对于丹尼尔
We always end up agreeing that devonhurst
去德文霍斯特是正确的选择
is the right thing for Daniel.
那也许我们该想想
Well, maybe we should start
对我们来说正确的选择
thinking about what's right for us.
我们的女儿因为我们没有打理院子
Our daughter is suffering because
而受了委屈
we won't fix up our own yard.
这不是我们的院子
It's not our yard.
你怎么能这么说 理查德
How can you say that, Richard? How?
我们在这里住了十二年
We've lived here for 12 years...
十二年来我们一直在说
...and for 12 years we've been
这只是暂时的 但事实并非如此
saying it's tempory, but it's not.
这是我们的家
This is our home.
想要住在一个为之自豪的地方 难道错了吗
Is it wrong to wanna live somewhere you can be proud of?
想攒够钱送孩子去念大学 难道错了吗
To have enough to send your kids to college?
也许是时候该考虑政府资助了
Maybe it's time we considered government care.
我不会让我弟弟去其他地方
We are not moving my brother.
他就比你自己的孩子还重要吗
He's more important than your own children?
- 爸爸 - 你怎么敢
- Dad! - How dare you!
别说了 爸爸 求你别说了
Stop it, dad! please, just stop.
对不起 朱莉安娜 这不是你的错
I'm sorry. Julianna, this is not your fault.
我们会解决的 我保证
We'll work this out, i promise.
那是我第一次听到
That was the first time i ever heard
我的父母相互大喊大叫
my parents really yell at each other.
今晚的事我很抱歉
I'm sorry about tonight.
那天晚上他们都来了我房间
That night they each came into my room.
爸爸给我讲了他弟弟的事
My father talked about his brother
还有自己多么爱他
and how much he loved him...
以及他对他父母做出的
...and how he promised his parents
一定会照顾好弟弟的承诺
he'd always take care of him.
妈妈告诉了我她有多爱爸爸
My mother talked about how much she loved my father...
出于他的能力和善良
...for his strength and kind heart.
当她给我晚安吻的时候
When she kissed me good night...
她低语道 在她得到所有的赐予中
...she whispered that of all her
我是最棒的一个
many blessings, I was her best.
我为爸爸感到难过
I felt sorry for my father.
也为妈妈感到难过
I felt sorry for my mother.
但更重要的是 拥有他们 我真的很幸运
But most of all, i felt lucky for me that they were mine.
我想了想自己开始打理庭院的原因
I wanted to think the reason i started working on my yard...
和布莱斯没有关系
...had nothing to do with Bryce.
只是为了让我家变得更好
it was about making our house better.
在他那样对待我的鸡蛋之后
After what he did with the eggs,
我为什么还要在意他的想法
why should i care what he thought?
但我在意
But i did.
你是在修剪它还是打算把它劈死
Are you pruning that or trying to hack it to death
嗨 我是切特 邓肯 布莱斯的外公
Hi. i'm chet duncan, Bryce's grandfather.
抱歉过了这么久
Sorry it's taken me so long to
才过来打招呼
come over and introduce myself.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
所以你打算把它们都修剪到一个高度吗
So are you trimming all these to the same height
是啊 我的确这么想过 不过我也说不好
Well, yeah, that's what i was thinking, but i don't know.
你觉得把它们砍掉会好些吗
Do you think it would look better to take them out
这些可是红豆杉灌木 可以被修剪得很好
Oh, these are hicksii shrubs. these will prune up nicely.
邓肯先生
Listen, Mr. duncan.
叫我切特就好
Call me chet.
切特
Chet.
如果你是因为布莱斯的话过来
If you're here because of what Bryce said...
那我不需要帮忙
...i don't need your help.
我是在报纸上看到你的
Read about you in the paper.
如果是蕾妮 她也会和你一起坐在那棵树上
Renee would've sat up in that tree with you.
她一定会整晚坐在上面
She would've sat up there all night.
蕾妮是谁
Renee?
我妻子
My wife.
你让我想起了她
You remind me a lot of her.
我们在院子里忙活了好几周
We worked on the yard for weeks.
几周来 我们一边干活 一边聊天
And the whole time we worked, we talked.
- 就在这里 - 完美
- right there - perfect, yeah.
他想知道关于无花果树的事
He wanted to know more about the sycamore tree.
而且他完全懂得
He knew exactly what it meant...
整体大于部分之和的道理
...about the whole being greater than the sum of its parts.
他说人也是一样的
He said it was the same with people...
只是有的人 从整体上看更加浅薄
...but sometimes with people, the whole could be less.
我觉得这很有趣
I thought that was pretty interesting.
我开始审视
I started looking at people i'd
那些我从小学就认识的人
known since elementary school...
想看看他们从整体来看
...trying to figure out if they were more
是比部分之和更好还是更坏
or less than the sum of their parts.
切特说得对 很多人的确不如他们的部分之和
Chet was right. a lot of them were less.
在所有的同学里 只有一个
Of all my classmates, the one person
我无法准确定位的人 布莱斯
I couldn't seem to place was Bryce.
如果是以前 我会很肯定
Until recently, i would've said with absolute certainty...
他的整体要远远地
...that he was greater, far greater,
大于部分之和
than the sum of his parts.
但现在我不那么确定了
But now i wasn't so sure.
看起来很棒 朱莉 你做得很好
It's looking good, Juli. nice job.
谢谢 大部分是切特的功劳
Thanks. chet did most of it.
我很抱歉做了那些事
I'm sorry for what i did.
我就是搞不懂 布莱斯
I just don't get it, Bryce.
你为什么不直接告诉我
Why didn't you just tell me?
他真的心怀歉意吗
Was he really sorry?
还是说 他说这些话
Or was he just saying these things
只为了让自己好过些
to make himself feel better?
然后我想 也许我只是
Then i thought maybe i just wanted him
期待他能比他的部分之和更好
to be more than the sum of his parts.
但当我直视他的眼睛
But as i looked into his eyes...
那双光彩夺目的眼睛
...those dazzling eyes...
第一次
...for the first time...
我很确定布莱斯 洛斯基是另一种的人
...I was pretty sure that Bryce Loski was less.
我们要邀请贝克一家来共进晚餐
We're going to invite the Bakers over for dinner.
- 什么 - 我怎么都不知道 妈妈
- What? - I don't know, Mom.
我觉得这个主意很棒
I think that's a marvelous idea.
佩茜 为什么这么做
Patsy, what purpose does this serve?
特瑞娜 贝克是个很好的人
Trina Baker is a very nice person.
- 而且马特和马克真的很酷 - 我讨厌装酷的孩子
- and Matt and Mark are really cool. - I hate cool.
这事我们多年前就该做了
Something we should've done years ago.
没错 但我们以前没做 现在也不能做
Yeah, but we didn't. and now we can't.
早过时了
The statute of limitations has run out.
我们一定要请贝克家来吃晚餐
We're having the Bakers over for dinner.
如果是因为我昨晚说的话 我道歉 行吗
If this is about what i said last night, i'm sorry, okay
但是 就算邀请他们来吃晚餐
But, you know, having them over for
他的弟弟也治不好了
dinner is not gonna fix his brother.
这是个正式的晚宴
It's going to be a sit-down dinner.
我希望所有人都能穿得正式些
And i expect everyone to dress accordingly.
天哪 我们就不能烤个肉吗
Oh, god. can't we just have a barbecue
我说过 正式的晚宴
It's going to be a sit-down dinner.
杀了我吧
Just shoot me now.
可得小心愿望成真
Careful what you wish for.
事情就是这样
So that was it.
不久以后 我就会和朱莉 贝克
A dress-up, sit-down dinner with Juli
盛装吃晚宴
Baker was in my immediate future.
这让我在学校看到朱莉的时候更不自在了
And that made seeing Juli at school more uncomfortable.
我发现自己会在课上盯着她看
I found myself staring at her in class.
当她的秀发从肩膀上滑落
And the way her hair fell back over her shoulders...
她看起来就像报纸上照片里的人
...she looked just like the picture in the newspaper.
达娜 特雷斯勒注意到了我的视线
Dana tressler caught me watching.
如果我不快速地做出反应
If i didn't do something fast,
传言就会像野火一样散播
this could spread like wildfire.
她的头发上有只蜜蜂
There was a bee in her hair.
看 往那边飞了
See, there it goes.
我没看见蜜蜂
There's no bee.
从窗子飞出去了
It flew out the window.
我庆幸自己躲过一劫
I convinced myself i'd dodged a bullet.
我必须让朱莉从我脑海中消失
I had to put Juli out of my mind.
把注意力放在更重要的事情上 比如学习
Keep the focus on the important stuff like schoolwork.
我的弱点就在于容易紧张
My weakness was unnerving.
我要用你的削笔刀
I need your sharpener.
- 你敲门了吗 - 嘿
- You ever heard of knocking - Hey,
你藏什么呢 老爸的花花公子杂志吗
what you got there? Dad's Playboy?
不关你的事
None of your business.
- 替我向十月女郎问好 - 快出去
- Give my best to Miss October. - Get out.
- 你还是忙着替自己问候吧 - 真恶心
- Or should i say your best ha, ha. - You're disgusting.
又躲过一劫
Another disaster avoided.
我的生活简直到处埋着地雷
My life had become a minefield.
- 嘿 兄弟 - 嘿
- Hey, man. - hey.
这是什么
What's this?
哇哦
Whoa.
不是你想的那样
It's not what you think.
好吧 就是你想的那样 让我解释一下
Okay, it is what you think, but i can explain.
好吧 我没法解释 我们能待会儿再说吗
Okay, i can't explain. can we just talk about it later?
随便你
Whatever you say.
我得和什么人倾诉一下
I had to talk to someone.
加雷特怎么样 也许他能帮我回归正轨
Why not garrett? Maybe he could help me get back on track.
加雷特对心理问题非常了解
Garrett was surprisingly sensitive in matters of the heart.
Orange
字幕组
你疯了吗 那可是朱莉 贝克 你讨厌她
Are you freaking mental? Juli Baker. you hate her.
所以才奇怪啊 我不觉得她讨厌了
That's what's weird. i don't think I do.
我没法不想着她
I can't stop thinking about her.
- 你这样很糟糕 兄弟 - 那我该怎么办
- You got it bad, man. - Well, what do I do
你得把它扼杀在摇篮里
Well, you gotta nip this in the bud.
这算不上是真的感情
These aren't real emotions.
- 不是吗 - 你只是因为鸡蛋的事觉得愧疚
- They're not? - You feel guilty because of the egg thing.
是啊 我还嘲笑了她家的院子
Yeah, and i insulted her yard.
就是啊 反正那地方的确很糟糕
Exactly. of course, the place is a dump anyways.
又不能怪她父亲把所有的钱
It was not her fault. Her dad's got a retarded brother and
都花在智障弟弟的身上
all their money goes to helping him.
一个智障 那你就更能明白一些事了
A retard? Well, shoot, that ought to tell you something.
- 明白什么事 - 朱莉的事
- About what? - About Juli.
什么意思
What are you saying?
有其叔 必有其侄呗 朋友
The apple doesn't fall far from the tree. My friend.
我简直不敢相信 我想大声呵斥他
I couldn't believe it. I wanted to yell at him.
告诉他 他并不像我一样了解朱莉
Tell him that he didn't know Juli like i did.
但我只是这样说 对哦
But all that came out was: Heh, oh.
- 没错 - 是吧
- right. - yeah.
没错 我一会儿再和你说
Right. um, I'll talk to you later.
放学后我本该去找加雷特的
I was supposed to go to garrett's after school...
但我不能见到他
...but i couldn't be around him.
他太过分了
He'd crossed the line.
而和他在同一战线的
And standing right next to him
还有我爸爸
across that line was my father.
我不在乎他们怎么想
I didn't care what they thought.
我喜欢朱莉 贝克
I liked Juli Baker.
每个周日早晨 家里都很平静
Sunday mornings are peaceful in our house.
爸爸会睡懒觉
My dad lets himself sleep in.
妈妈也松懈了做早餐
My mother lets herself not fix breakfast.
如果不是哥哥们很早就出去找乐队的人
If my brothers have been out late playing with their band...
中午之前你都感觉不到他们的存在
...you won't even know they're around till noon.
但这个周日 我起床时有种奇怪的感觉
But this sunday, i woke up feeling weird.
我得做点什么来摆脱
I had to do something to shake off
对布莱斯的矛盾心情
the confused feelings about Bryce...
那些感情又悄悄地回到我心里了
...that were starting to creep back in.
你真的把院子打理好了
You really did it, didn't you heh.
- 为你感到骄傲 - 谢谢 爸爸
- Proud of you. - Thanks, dad.
- 你去哪儿 - 去看看丹尼尔 今天是他的生日
- Where you going? - To see daniel. It's his birthday.
我想和你一起去
I wanna come with you.
亲爱的 还是好好享受这个早晨吧 和妈妈待着
Oh, honey, just enjoy the morning, stay with your mom.
不 爸爸 我想去
No, dad. I wanna come.
听着 宝贝
Sweetheart, listen.
有时 丹尼尔他
Sometimes, with daniel...
我要去 爸爸
I'm coming, dad.
那好吧
Okay.
我们最好给你妈妈留个字条
We'd better leave a note for your mother.
这么多年来 我从未看望过丹尼尔叔叔
In all the years, i'd never visited my uncle daniel.
我不知道为什么 这总是爸爸会独自去做的事
I don't know why. It was always something my dad did alone.
去德文霍斯特的路上
We didn't say much to each other on the
我们没怎么说话 但我不在意
drive to devonhurst,but I didn't care.
我只是很喜欢和爸爸待在一起
I just liked being with my dad.
不知为何 这种沉默似乎比话语
Somehow the silence seemed to connect
更能让我们的心连在一起
us in a way that words never could.
居民们把清扫地面作为疗程的一部分
The residents tend to the grounds as part of their therapy.
这需要花些时间去适应 不过他们是好人
It takes some getting used to. they're good people, though.
丹尼尔
Daniel?
Daniel.
理查德 你来了
Richard! you're here!
理查德为我的生日来了
Richard for my birthday.
谁 理查德 谁啊
Who? richard, who? who?
谁啊 理查德 是谁啊
Who? who? richard, who? who?
丹尼尔 丹尼尔 这是朱莉安娜 我的女儿
Daniel, daniel, it's Julianna. it's my daughter.
你的侄女
Your niece.
朱莉安娜
Julianna.
- 哈 朱莉安娜  - 生日快乐 丹尼尔叔叔
- ha, Julianna. - happy birthday, uncle daniel.
哈哈哈 理查德 今天是我生日
Ha-ha-ha. richard. it's my birthday.
我有你的照片 朱莉安娜 我有你的照片
I have your pictures, Julianna. i have your pictures.
我们给你准备了一个礼物
We have a present for you.
一幅拼图 拼图 拼图
A puzzle? a puzzle, richard?
不仅仅是拼图
Not just a puzzle.
一幅拼图和一个
A puzzle and a...
风车
...pinwheel.
风车 谢谢你 理查德
A pinwheel! thank you, richard.
是的
Yes.
橙色的 去外面吧 外面吧 理查德
Orange. outside? outside, richard?
你想去外面 好吧
You wanna go outside? all right,
我们去麦克 埃利奧特吧
we'll go to McElliot's
- 我们走到那儿去买冰淇淋 - 冰淇淋
- we'll walk out there for an ice cream. - ice cream!
哦 不不不 不行
Oh, no. no, no, we can't.
丹尼尔不喜欢冰淇淋
Daniel doesn't like ice cream.
- 我喜欢冰淇淋啊 理查德  -  我只是在开玩笑
- i do like ice cream, richard. - i'm only kidding.
- 我知道你喜欢冰淇淋 - 啊
- i know you like ice cream. - ahh!
你超爱冰淇淋 好了 来吧
You love ice cream. all right, come on.
麦克 埃利奧特冰淇淋与糖果店
- 拿着 好吗 - 啊
- here you go. got it? - ah!
给你的
Here you go.
今天是我生日
It's my birthday.
棒棒糖 今天是我生日
Lollipop. it's my birthday.
你喜欢吗 哦
You like it? oh!
- 好了 丹尼尔 好了 等一下
- all right, daniel. okay, wait,
等一下 - 冰淇淋
wait. - ice cre
- 我的冰淇淋 我的冰淇淋  - 没事的 丹尼尔
- my ice cream. my ice cream. ugh! - it's okay. daniel.
丹尼尔
Daniel!
丹尼尔 算了吧 我给你再
Daniel! leave it, i'll get y...
冰淇淋掉在地上了 冰淇淋掉在地上了
Ice cream on the floor. ice cream on the floor.
你能去给他再买一个甜筒吗
Would you go get him another cone?
- 好的 - 我想要冰淇淋 理查德
- yeah. - i need ice cream, richard!
今天是我生日 理查德 今天是我生日
It's my birthday, richard. it's my birthday!
冰淇淋 理查德 冰淇淋 理查德
Ice cream, richard! ice cream, richard!
停下 停下来
Stop! stop it!
- 我需要它 - 停下 停下来
- i need it! - stop it! stop it!
- 来了  - 冰淇淋
- here we go. - ice cream!
- 理查德 - 好了 好了 我有冰淇淋了
- richard! - okay, okay. i've got some ice cream.
生日冰淇淋 真棒 理查德
Birthday ice cream. that's good, richard.
对不起 他以前没有这样过
I'm so sorry. he hasn't done anything like that...
我过去经常听我爸爸谈起
I'd often heard my father talk about
生活对于丹尼尔有多艰难
how difficult life was for Daniel
但直到此刻 我才真正明白
But i never really understood it until now.
- 没错 就这样 - 橙色的
- yeah, there you go. - heh. orange.
走在回去的路上 丹尼尔的举止就好像什么都没发生过一样
On the walk back, daniel acted like nothing had happened.
另一边 另一边
Other way. other way.
在回家的车程上 我爸告诉我 在我们出生之前
On the ride home, my dad told me that uncle daniel...
丹尼尔叔叔曾经跟他和妈妈住在一起
...used to live with him and mom before we were born.
但不久后 这变得实在太困难了
But after a while, it became too difficult.
当我们回到家后 一切看似如常
When we got home, everything looked the same.
但其实不是
But it wasn't.
在今天之前 丹尼尔对于我来说只是一个名字
Before today, daniel had always been just a name to me.
现在他是这个家的一员了
Now he was part of the family.
- 嘿 - 嘿
- hey. - hey.
怎么样
How'd it go?
我很高兴我去了
I'm glad i went.
我也很高兴你去了
I'm glad you went too.
特琳娜 今天是周日 你干嘛要拖地
Trina, it's sunday. what are you doing mopping the floor?
帕蒂 罗斯基邀请了我们周五晚上过去吃晚餐
Patty Loski invited us over for dinner friday night.
难道不应该她去拖她的地板吗
Shouldn't she be mopping her floor?
还是她借了我们的
Or did she ask to borrow ours?
有点紧张
Nervous energy.
- 她邀请了我们全部人 - 是 她邀请了
-Did she invite all of us? - Yes, she did.
包括我们的朋友 沙门氏菌吗
Even our friend sal monella?
理查德
Richard.
搞什么 都这么多年过去了
Why, after all these years?
她说她感觉很糟糕
Well, she said she felt really bad
他们过去没有邀请我们
that they hadn't invited us before?
很明显 他们想要更好地了解我们
...and apparently they want to get to know us better.
你想去
And you wanna go?
好吧 她坚持要
Well, she insisted.
而且我也觉得这很好
And i think it would be really nice.
好吧
All right.
我们去吧
We'll go.
我并不对和罗斯基一家吃饭感到兴奋
I wasn't too thrilled about dinner with the Loskis...
但我能看得出来 这对我妈来说很重要
...but i could see it meant a lot to my mother.
第二天 到了学校 我似乎无法集中注意力
At school the next day, i couldn't seem to concentrate.
我的思绪总是回到丹尼尔身上
My thoughts kept running back to daniel.
我想知道 我的祖父母有这样一个儿子
I wondered what my grandparents hadg
都经历了些什么
gone through having a son like him?
当现实打断了他们的生活
...when reality interrupted.
- 布莱斯 洛斯基喜欢你 - 什么
- Bryce Loski likes you. - what?
他暗恋你
He's got a big crush on you.
你在说些什么
What are you talking about? Bryce
布莱斯 罗斯基才没有喜欢我
Loski does not have a crush on me .
哦 真的吗 在科学课上 我抓住了他在盯着你看
Oh, yeah? in science, i caught him staring at you.
然后他就说你的头发里有一只蜜蜂
He said it was because there was a bee in your hair.
这还不是最蹩脚的掩饰吗
Is that the lamest cover-up or what?
或许真的有一只蜜蜂
Maybe there was a bee.
被你吸引过去的唯一一只蜜蜂 叫做 布 莱 斯
The only bee you're attracting is b-r-y-c-e.
我跟你说 那男孩彻底沦陷了
I'm telling you, that boy is lost in love land.
- 跟我来 - 去哪儿
- come on. - where?
我看见他跟加里德偷偷跑掉了 来吧
I saw him sneaking off with garrett. come on.
你是疯了吗 朱莉 贝克 你讨厌她
Are you freaking mental? Juli Baker. you hate her.
这才是奇怪的地方 我并不觉得如此
That's what's so weird. i don't think i do.
我没法不想她
I can't stop thinking about her.
- 这可严重了 兄弟 - 我该怎么办
-You got it bad, man - What do I do?
你必须在萌芽状态就抽身
You gotta nip this in the bud.
- 这些并不是真正的感情 - 不是吗
- These are not real emotions - They're not?
不是的 你只是为鸡蛋的事情感到内疚
Nah, You feel guilty because of the egg thing.
是的 我侮辱了她的院子
Yeah, and i insulted her yard.
没错 那地方本来就像个垃圾场
Exactly. the place is a dump anyways.
这并不是她的错 她爸有一个弱智的弟弟
It's not her fault. Her dad's got a retarded brother and
他们的所有钱都用来帮他了
all their money goes to helping him
一个弱智 那说明了很多啊
A retard? well, that ought to tell you something.
- 关于什么 - 关于朱莉的事啊
- About what - About Juli.
你在说些什么
What are you saying?
有其叔必有其侄啊 朋友
The apple doesn't fall far from the tree, my friend.
没错
Yeah.
我稍后跟你聊
I'll talk to you later.
好的
Okay.
对不起 我以为
I'm sorry. i thought...
没事 这没什么
It's okay. it's fine.
而且确实没事了
And it was.
因为现在我的疑惑都没了
Because now my confusion was gone.
我确定我不再喜欢布莱斯 洛斯基了
I was sure i no longer liked Bryce Loski.
妈 你在试着
Mom, are you trying to make the
让贝克一家感到彻底廉价吗
Bakers feel totally worthless
我想要友好些
I want it to be nice.
- 为什么你还没穿戴好 - 我会去的
- and why aren't you dressed? - i'm going.
我想要在朱莉面前帅气些
I wanted to look good for Juli.
但我不想让她以为
But i didn't want her to think that
我是为了她打扮的
i wanted to look good for her
有一条细微的界线
It was a fine line.
一条很细微的界线
A very fine line.
布莱斯 他们到了 快下来
Bryce, they're here. come on down.
来了
Coming!
嘿 快进来
Hey, come on in.
进来 进来 我的腰围要没了
Come in, come in. - there goes the waistline.
我很高兴 你们能来 丽内塔 斯蒂芬 客人来了
I'm glad you could make it. lynetta, steven, company's here.
来了 这是什么 自制馅饼吗
Coming! - what is this? homemade pie?
没错 这是山核桃和蓝莓芝士蛋糕
Yes, it's pecan and blueberry cheesecake.
把它们放去厨房吧
Let's take them to the kitchen.
- 大家好 - 嘿 你看上去真不错
- hi, guys. - hey, looking good.
- 这是我爸爸 - 你好 我是丽内塔
- this is my dad. - hi, i'm lynetta.
- 嗨 很高兴终于见到你们 - 很高兴见到你
- hi, nice to finally meet you. - nice to meet you too.
嘿 大画家
Hey, big guy.
嘿 史蒂文 你好吗
Hey, Steven. how are you?
我们早就该聚聚了 进来吧
We should've done this a long time ago. come on in.
你们家看起来很漂亮
This is a cool place.
还好啦 来吧 给你们看看我的房间
Yeah, it's all right. come on, i'll show you my room.
你一定得听听我们写的新歌
You gotta hear this new song we wrote.
很不错
It's so good.
嗨
Hi.
你看起来很漂亮
You look nice.
我听到你跟加勒特
I heard you and garrett making
在图书馆取笑我叔叔
fun of my uncle in the library
我不想跟你说话
And i don't wanna speak to you.
现在不想 以后也不想
Not now, not ever.
- 我觉得你可以 - 但你提议是
- And I say you can. - But what you're proposing...
需要一台永动机
...would require a perpetual-motion
那是不可能的
machine, so it's not possible.
如果你用一个中性导体
If you had two opposite charged
传导正负两极
poles with a neutral conductor.
永动机
Perpetual motion?
我站在这儿 心如死灰
Here i was, dying inside, and they
他们居然在谈论永动机
were talking about Perpetual motion.
朱莉是怎么知道这些的
And how did Juli know about all that stuff?
好了 大家伙 晚餐准备好了 琳内特
Come on, everybody, dinner's ready. Lynnette!
吃饭啦
Dinner!
朱莉 我能跟你聊聊吗
Juli, can i talk to you?
加勒特说的不对 我知道
It was wrong, what garrett said. i know it.
他在说的时候你知道是错的吗
Did you know it was wrong when he said it?
是的 我本想打他来着
Yeah. i wanted to punch him.
但我们当时在图书馆
But we were in the library.
所以你就赞同他 和他一起笑了吗
So instead you just agreed with him and laughed.
是的
Yeah.
那说明你就是个懦夫
Then that makes you a coward.
整顿饭我都坐在朱莉对面
I had to sit across from Juli for an entire dinner.
我爸爸说的对
My dad was right.
我们应该吃烧烤
We should have barbecued.
我想说能和你们
I just want to say how wonderful it
一起共进晚餐真是太好了
is to have you share a meal with us.
也许这是一个开始
May it be the first of many.
呛到我了
Wrong pipe.
嗯 我们也很开心
Well, we couldn't be happier.
我们非常激动能来这儿做客
We are just all so thrilled to be here.
朱莉 你把你家院子收拾的很不错啊
Juli, you did a really nice job on your yard.
谢谢 切特帮了大忙
Thanks. Chet was a big help.
是啊 我知道
Yeah, i know.
你得告诉我秘诀
You gotta tell me your secret. i can't
我都请不动老爷子干活
get him to do a thing around here.
- 史蒂文 - 我开玩笑啦
- steven. - i kid.
我告诉你们 我们社区真的开始活跃起来了
I'm telling you, the neighborhood is really coming to life.
我是说 那栋新房子马上完工
I mean, that new house is taking shape.
哪栋
Which one?
你知道 就是他们砍掉那棵大丑树的地方
You know, the one where they cut down that big ugly tree.
我想说很多人都
I wanted to say that a lot of people
喜欢那棵树
liked that tree.
但我没说 我不想和我爸作对
But I didn't,I didn't want to go against my dad.
有些人将那棵树视为
Some people thought that tree was
这个社区的珍宝
the jewel of the neighborhood.
是啊 嗯 人各有喜好
Yeah, well, there's no accounting for taste.
马特 马克 马克 马特
So, matt, mark, mark, matt...
你们俩 马上就要毕业了是不是
You guys are, uh, gonna be graduating soon, huh?
是啊 总算是
Yeah, thank god.
你们不喜欢高中吗
You don't like high school?
- 你开玩笑吗 - 没有
- You kidding? - No.
高中生活是我人生最美好的时光
High school was the best time of my life.
- 对我们来说不是 - 是啊 我们已经受够了
- not for us, no. - yeah, we've had enough of that scene.
啊
Ah.
那上大学肯定是没希望了
so college school probably out of the question，huh?
不是 有可能念啊
No, it's a possibility.
事实上他们已经被
They've actually been accepted...
- 好几所大学录取了 - 是的
- at several places already. - yes, they have.
真的吗
Really?
那太好了
Well, that's good.
但 我们准备先玩段时间音乐
But, um, we're gonna give music a shot first.
- 是吗 - 哦 他们真的很有天赋
- really? - oh, they are very talented.
哦 他们的乐队很棒
Oh, their band is really boss.
他们制作了一堆录音样带 真的很好听
They did a bunch of demos and they're really cool.
谢谢夸奖 小琳
Thanks, lyn.
当我和史蒂文刚认识的时候 他也在一个乐队演奏
When Steven and i first met, he was playing in a band.
你在乐队里演奏过吗
You played in a band?
他是一个很棒的萨克斯演奏者
He was a wonderful saxophone player.
- 酷 你现在还演奏吗 - 嗯
- cool. you still play? - well, l...
如果你想的话 你可以抽时间过来一起玩
Well, if you want, .
呃 你们
Uh, you...
不 我是说
No, i mean... heh.
我很久都不吹了
That's not me anymore.
你们俩有没有在观众面前表演过
Have you boys ever performed in front of an audience?
很多次了
A lot of times.
马特和马克谈论
The more matt and mark talked
他们的音乐造诣越多
about their musical exploits.
我爸爸就越沉默
...the quieter my dad got.
他不时地努力挤出一个假笑
He tried to plaster on a smile now and then...
但在心里他看起来很悲伤
...but underneath he seemed really sad.
但我爸妈一开始就不喜欢他
But my parents didn't like him at first.
共和党派极力的反对这项新决议
Republicans fought like crazy against the new deal.
晚餐剩下的时间都过的不痛不痒
The rest of the evening was painless enough.
但整顿饭下来 朱莉没再跟我说一句话
But through it all, Juli didn't say a word to me.
连看都不看我一眼
Never even looked at me.
直到她要回去了
Until she was about to leave.
对不起刚进来的时候对你说话很冲
I'm sorry i was so angry when we first came in.
我觉得大家都度过了美好的时光
I think everyone had a good time.
你妈妈真的很好 邀请我们做客
Your mom was really nice to invite us.
回头见
See you.
她的道歉让事情更僵硬
Her apology made things worse.
— 嘿 等下我 - 我知道我没有被原谅
- hey wait for me. - I knew i wasn't forgiven.
就像是我根本就不重要
It was like i wasn't even important
不值得她生气一样
enough to hold a grudge against.
嗯 我觉得他们一家都很讨人喜欢
Well, i think they're a delightful family.
男孩子们跟我想的完全不一样
Those boys were nothing like i expected.
我觉得他们都很优秀
I thought they were very nice young men.
- 小兔崽子 - 什么
- hoodlums. - what?
你觉得他们买得起录音设备吗
How you think they can afford all that recording gear?
史蒂文 拜托 你别信口开河 胡说八道
Steven, please. you can't just make an accusation like that.
别那么单纯 缺心眼子
Don't be so naive, patsy.
你知道录样带有多贵吗
Do you know how expensive it is to record a demo?
他们可能偷了轮毂 为了凑钱
They're probably stealing hubcaps, for chris sake.
你真是个大混蛋
You are such an asshole.
你到底怎么回事啊
What is the matter with you?
去死吧
Go to hell.
不准这么跟我说话
Don't you talk to me like that.
史蒂文 站住
Steven, stop!
没人能在我家那么跟我说话
Nobody talks to me like that in my house
回来
Stop!
我见过我爸爸生气的样子 这次不一样
I'd seen my father angry before, but this was different.
那晚当我躺在床上
As i lay in bed that night...
我在想我爸爸为什么
...i thought about how my dad
总是瞧不起贝克一家人
always looked down Bakers
总是叫他们废物
And how he'd called them trash and
取笑贝克先生的画
made fun of mr. Baker's paintings.
现在我意识到他只是在跟自己生气
And now i realized he was just mad at himself.
但为什么呢
But why?
朱莉说我是懦夫
Juli called me a coward.
难道我爸爸也是一个懦夫
Was it possible my dad was a coward too?
我不知道
I didn't know.
这又有什么区别呢
What difference did it make?
朱莉 贝克从我的生活中消失了
Juli Baker was out of my life.
或者是 更准确地说
Or, more accurately...
我从她的生活中消失了
...i was out of hers.
在我为去洛斯奇家做客换衣服时
As i was getting dressed for the Loskis' dinner party...
我发现自己一直盯着
...i found myself staring at the
我父亲送给我的画
painting my father gave me.
又开始一肚子怨气
...and became furious all over again.
布莱斯从没都没把我当过朋友
Bryce had never been a friend to me, ever.
他没有跟我一起保护那棵树
He hadn't taken my side about the tree...
他扔掉了我给的鸡蛋
...he'd thrown away my eggs...
他还取笑我的叔叔
...and he made fun of me at my uncle's expense.
当我妈妈叫我出发时
When my mother called that it was time to go...
朱莉 快点 我们迟了
Juli, let's go, we're late!
我想了千百个理由想告诉她
I went out with every intention of telling
我不想去洛斯奇家吃晚饭
her that i wasn't going to the Loskis' home for dinner
拿下这个 我需要再快速
Please hold these. i need to check my
检查下我的头发
hair really quickly one more time.
- 亲爱的 你的发型很完美了 - 真的吗
- honey,your hair is perfect. - really?
但她看起来很开心
But she looked so happy...
她为做那些派
...and she'd gone to so much trouble
花了很多心思 我不能
over the pies.I could't
哦 哦 我的天啊 哦 天啊 差点毁了
Ooh! oh, my gosh. oh, god, what a disaster.
好了 你拿着一个 你拿着这个
Okay. here, hold one, and you hold this.
- 我不想拿 - 我不会让你拿的
- i don't wanna hold it. - i won't have you hold it.
走吧 孩子们
Let's go, boys.
但这并不意味我必须对布莱斯友善
But that didn't mean i had to be nice to Bryce.
我不想跟你说话
And i don't wanna speak to you.
现在不想 以后也不想
Not now, not ever.
有主动权的感觉很好
It felt good to take charge.
我觉得自己能掌控一切 我告诉布莱斯我的想法
I felt strong, in control. i told Bryce what i thought...
我打算晚上不再
...and i was determined not to talk
跟他说话
to him for the rest of evening.
吃饭的时候 我突然想到
At dinner it struck me that we were
我们在跟一群陌生人吃饭
sharing a meal with a group of strangers.
我们跟洛斯奇家做邻居好几年了
We'd lived across the street from the Loskis for years...
但除了切特 我根本不了解这些人
...but except for chet, i didn't know these people at all.
洛斯奇先生在外面看起来光鲜体面
Mr. Loski was clean and smooth on the outside...
但似乎看起来心里装着
...but it seemed like there was something
什么腐烂掉的东西
rotten buried just beneath the surface.
晚餐的最后 我感到很平静 就像旁观者
By the end of the evening, all i felt was detached, neutral.
没有争论 没有一点的愤怒
No fireworks, no leftover anger...
没有不安 什么都没有
...no flutters, nothing.
回头见
See you.
那晚我躺在床上感到很平静
I went to bed that night feeling peaceful.
- 你还好吗 - 嗯
- you okay? - yeah.
我很感激我有这样的家人
I was grateful that i had the family i had.
不用在乎布莱斯 洛斯基感觉很好
And it felt good to no longer care about Bryce Loski.
和贝克一家人的晚餐让我备受打击
The dinner with the Bakers had taken its toll on me.
然后学校一年一度的募捐活动来了
Then the annual school fundraiser arrived...
我发现自己又有了一堆新的烦恼
...and i found myself with a whole new set of problems.
我要做篮子男孩
I was a basketboy.
想要充分欣赏篮子男孩的耻辱盛况
To fully appreciate the humiliation of being a basketboy...
你需要知道的是 那些被选中的少数人
... all you need to know that the chosen few are
当着全校学生的面被拍卖给
auctioned off in front of the whole student of body
出价最高的女生
...to the highest-bidding females.
是的 从技术上讲 我们每个人要带
Yes, technically, each of us comes
午餐篮子
with a lunch basket
但我们还是不要自欺欺人了 这就是一个选美活动
...but let's not kid ourselves. this was a beefcake parade.
在这儿啊 我的偶像
There he is, my idol.
再说一句 你就死定了
One word, you're a dead man.
不 伙计 我是认真的 听着 你肯定不相信这个
No, man, i'm serious. listen, you won't believe this.
什么
What?
两个最火辣的小妞正在因为你撕逼
Two of the hottest chicks are fighting over you.
你在说什么啊
what are you talking about?
雪莉和米奇分手了
Sherry is breaking up with mitch
她和梅勒妮打算在拍卖会上对你进行一场竞价战
She and Melanie are having a bidding war over you.
我不在乎
I don't care.
你傻了吗 雪莉踹了米奇是因为你
Are you nuts? Sherry dumped mitch because of you.
你就是我的偶像
You're my idol.
虽然成为加勒特偶像获得了点安慰
As comforting as it was to be garrett's idol...
这并没有减少我对做
...it didn't diminish the horror
第9号篮子男孩的恐惧
of being a basketboy NO.9.
我只希望在学校举行拍卖会之前
And my only hope was that a giant tornado
能被一场大飓风夷为平地
would destroy the school before the big event.
几乎没可能
It was a long shot.
欢迎 大家
Welcome, everyone...
参加今年的梅菲尔德俱乐部拍卖会
...to this year's mayfield boosters club auction.
再一次 我们很高兴向大家介绍
Once again we are pleased to present...
二十位梅菲尔得最优秀的
...20 of mayfield's finest young
- 年轻人 - 布莱斯 布莱斯  布莱斯
- men... - Bryce,Bryce,Bryce
- 你来这儿干什么 - 朱莉坐在第三排
- what are you doing here? - Juli's in the third row.
- 那又怎么了 - 她拿着一把现金
- so? - so she's got a wad of cash.
- 胡说  - 千真万确
- bullshit. - bull-true.
我看见她在柜子旁数钱了
I saw her counting it by her locker.
现在
And now...
请热烈欢迎梅菲尔德学校
...please give a big mayfield school welcome...
你们的1963年篮子男孩
...to your 1963 basketboys.
朱莉带着钱 这是什么意思
Juli with cash? what did this mean?
难道她想为我竞价
Was it possible she was gonna bid on me?
第一位是 我们有请
First up, we have...
雷蒙德 休斯
...raymond hughes.
雷蒙德在象棋队
Raymond's on the chess team...
他的爱好包括邮票收集和玩悠悠球
...and his hobbies include stamp collecting and the yo-yo.
Orange
字幕组
记住了 当你竞价
Remember, when you bid...
你不仅会得到一枚英俊的休斯先生
...you'll not only be getting the handsome mr. hughes...
你还能享用到
...you'll also be enjoying...
美味的鸡肉沙拉三明治
...a lovely chicken-salad sandwich...
还有看起来很可口的芸豆蘸酱 还有
...and what looks to be a tasty bean dip, and...
哦 抱歉 是洋葱蘸酱
Oh. excuse me, onion dip.
还有一大块樱桃派
And a big slice of cherry pie.
好了 起拍价5美元
Okay, who will start the bidding at $5?
- 拍卖开始了 - 有人吗
- thus began the bidding - Anybody?
雷蒙德 休斯的拍卖 没人出价
Or in raymond hughes' case, the lack of bidding.
很好 成交
Very good, here we go.
- 5美元 - 成交
- five - Sold.
- 10美元 - 成交
- ten dollars - Sold.
- 15美元 - 成交
- fifteen - Sold.
快点 有人出10美元吗
Come on. do i hear 10?
10美元
Ten.
- 10美元 - 花生酱香蕉三明治
- Ten. - peanut-butter-and-banana sandwich.
15美元
Fifteen.
15美元成交
Sold for $15.
第八位是埃迪 特鲁洛克
Number eight is Eddie Trulock.
埃迪是辩论队的成员
Eddie is a member of the debate team.
现在我和拍卖台之间
Now only Eddie Trulock stood
只隔着埃迪 特鲁洛克
between me and the auction block
我对他的爱好不感兴趣
I wasn't interested in his hobbies
和他篮子里装了什么 毫无兴趣
or what was in his basket
我满脑子想的都是茱莉
All i could think of was Juli.
万一她对我出价了呢
What if she did bid on me?
万一她和雪莉还有梅兰妮竞价
What if she got in a bidding war with
结果输了呢
Sherry and melanie and lost out?
没有人出价吗
No bidders?
当我正沉迷于那种恐惧时
I was contemplating the horrors of this when...
八元
Eight dollars.
好的 八元
There you go. eight dollars,
这才对嘛 有更高的吗
that's more like it.Do i hear 10?
茱莉贝克竟然对埃迪 特鲁洛克出价
Juli Baker was bidding on Eddie Trulock?
她怎么可以对艾迪竞价呢
How could she bid on Eddie?
她怎么能对别人竞价呢
How could she bid on anyone?
茱莉贝克中标
Sold to Juli Baker.
下一位是九号篮子男孩布莱斯 洛斯基
Next is basketboy number nine, Bryce Loski.
我知道我应该站到前面去 但是我根本不想动
I knew i was supposed to step forward, but i couldn't move.
上前来 布莱斯 别害羞
Step up, Bryce, don't be shy.
迟到总比没到好
Better late than never. ha, ha.
布莱斯喜欢打棒球
Bryce likes to play baseball.
- 5美元 - 等等 我还没  - 10
- Five dollars  - Oh, well, wait until l...  - Ten
看来竞标已经开始咯
Well, it appears the bidding is underway.
15 20
- fifteen. - twenty.
Twenty-five
Thirty.
Thirty-five
Forty.
50元
Fifty dollars.
天呐
Oh, my.
50元
Fifty dollars. wh...
50元一次
Fifty going once.
50元两次
Fifty going twice.
雪莉 斯道尔小姐 50元中标
Sold to miss Sherry Stalls for $50.
史上最高纪录哦
An all-time record.
非常感激
Oh, the boosters will be very grateful
这么慷慨的捐款
for such a generous donation.
真奇怪
It's strange.
我正在 和全校最辣的女生一起共进午餐
Here i was, having lunch with the hottest girl in school...
我却一点也提不起劲来
...and i was miserable.
我们可以去湖边玩 我爸爸在那里有一间小木屋
We're going up to the lake. my dad has a cabin there...
你可以晒出超美的古铜色
...and you get the most outrageous tan.
因为茱莉就在 离我不到20尺的地方
Because less than 20 feet away from me was Juli.
我的茱莉 和艾迪楚拉克一起
My Juli with Eddie Trulock.
她在笑
She's laughing.
她在笑什么呢
What was she laughing about?
她怎么能坐在那里 笑得那么好看
How could she sit there and laugh and look so beautiful?
布莱斯 你还好吗
Bryce, are you all right?
嗯
What?
你在看什么
What are you staring at?
没什么
Nothing.
午餐真好吃 布莱斯
Lunch is really delicious, Bryce.
布莱斯 你有听我说话吗
Bryce, did you hear me?
午餐真的很好吃
This is a really delicious lunch.
我们可以不要聊肤色或者食物吗
Can we not talk about tans or food?
那你想要聊什么
Well, what do you wanna talk about?
不知道 也许 永动机
I don't know, perpetual motion?
你知道那个东西吗
do you know anything about that?
什么机
Perpetual what?
我不知道自己怎么回事
I don't know what came over me. it was
就像着了魔
like i was possessed or something.
茱莉 我有话对你说 什么事
- Juli, i gotta talk to you. - what?
怎么回事 布莱斯
What's going on, Bryce?
你在做什么
What are you doing?
布莱斯 住手
Bryce, stop it.
布莱斯 你连一垒都没上啊
Bryce, you didn't even make it to first base.
我要吻你啊
I'll kiss you. ha, ha.
茱莉 茱莉
Juli! Juli!
茱莉 等等 我们能谈谈吗
Juli, wait. can we talk?
茱莉
Juli!
你在搞什么 别烦我 盖瑞
- what's the matter with you? - leave me alone, garrett.
你跟全校最辣的女生约会
You get a date with the finest girl
却因为茱莉把它搞砸了
on campus and you blow it for Juli.
你不懂 我是完全不懂啊
- you wouldn't understand! - i completely don't understand!
我们在说茱莉贝克呀
We're talking about Juli Baker here.
噩梦般的邻居
Nightmare neighbor,
自以为是的讨厌鬼
know-it-all nuisance. The coop-coop babe.
闭嘴
Shut up!
你对她动心啦 你在搞什么
Hey, have you flipped? what's the matter with you?
你再这个样子
You know what, if you're gonna be like
我就不要和你做朋友了
this, i don't need the association.
好啊 因为我也不想要了 好 我也不要
- well, good, because neither do i. - yeah, neither do i!
回家的路上
As i walked home with the dirty dishes
脏盘子在篮子里乒乓作响
clanking inside my picnic basket
我满脑子想的 都是茱莉
...all i could think of was Juli.
我迷上她了 彻底迷上她了
I had flipped. completely.
喂
Hello?
您好 贝克太太 茱莉在吗
Oh, heh. hi, Mrs. Baker. is Juli there?
抱歉 布莱斯 茱莉不想说话
Oh. i'm sorry, Bryce. Juli doesn't wanna talk.
求求你 贝克太太 我想见见她
Please, Mrs. Baker. i gotta see her.
对不起 布莱斯
I'm sorry, Bryce.
她把自己锁在房间里了
But i'm afraid she's locked herself in her room.
那天晚上 我试图早点上床睡觉
I tried to go to bed early that night...
但我睡不着
...but i couldn't sleep.
我从我家窗户 望着她家 好几个小时
I watched her house from my window for hours.
我必须想个办法 让她明白我的感觉
I had to find a way to show her how i felt.
周一早上 上学途中
Monday morning, as i made my way into school...
我正在考虑要嫁给
...i was deciding which of the
艾佛利兄弟二重唱的哪一个
everly brothers i'd rather marry
唐娜崔斯勒迫使 布莱斯 回到我的脑海中
...when Dana Tressler forced Bryce back into my brain.
茱莉 名单出来了
Juli. the list is out.
你的菜榜上有名哦 九号
There he is, number nine, your main dish.
布莱斯 洛斯基不是我的菜
Bryce Loski's not my main dish.
哦 你还在节食吗 不是节食 唐娜
- oh, you're sticking to your diet. - it's not a diet, Dana.
我不喜欢他了 那就好
- i'm over him, okay? - I'm glad to hear it.
因为有传言说
Because rumor has it Sherry's
雪莉已经盯上他了
already staking her claim on him.
雪莉 雪莉 斯道尔
Sherry? Sherry Stalls?
丽兹 梅西 名单出来了
Oh, Liz. Macy. the list is up.
那天下午 我发现我自己
That afternoon, i found myself
满脑子都在想篮子男孩拍卖会
obsessing about the Basketboy auction.
我感觉得到 自己又开始想布莱斯了
I could feel myself backsliding about Bryce.
就算雪莉喜欢他 我为什么要在乎
But why should i care if Sherry liked him?
我根本不应该想他
I shouldn't even be thinking about him.
我必须忘记他
I had to rise above this.
布莱斯 洛斯基已经走出我的人生了
Bryce Loski was no longer in my life.
拍卖会的早上 我快奔溃了
On the morning of the auction, i was on edge.
我发现自己 莫名其妙的
I found myself, without even knowing how
盯着我卖蛋的钱
it happened, staring at my egg money.
我需要一个策略
I needed a strategy.
非常简单
It was simple.
如果我把钱留在家里 诱惑就留在家里了
If i left my money at home, i'd leave temptation with it.
当我遇见史杜比太太的时候 我的策略失败了
My strategy suffered a setback when i ran into Mrs. steuby.
茱莉安娜
Julianna.
亲爱的
Hello, dear.
真抱歉 我拖了这么久才给你
I'm so sorry it's taken me so long to get this to you...
但我早上一直没有碰到你
...but i keep missing you in the morning.
史杜比太太 我不要 你不用给我
Mrs. steuby, I don't want that. you don't have to...
别傻了 你应得的
Don't be ridiculous. I'm gonna pay you.
我要付你钱的
- i'm going to pay you. - I  don't
我不要这个
want that it.
我希望你拿着
Yeah, i want you to go out and
给你自己买点东西
buy yourself festival.
七分裤吧
Pedal pushers. ha, ha.
史杜比太太 回见 亲爱的
- Mrs. steuby. - bye, dear.
史杜比太太 我不想要七分裤
- Mrs. steuby, i don't want pedal pushers.
别说傻话了 你穿起来会很好看的
- no, no. you'll look great.
没关系
It's okay.
没关系 没什么大不了的 假装我没钱就好了
It's okay. no big deal. just pretend like i don't have it.
我听说你打算对布莱斯出价
I hear you're planning to bid on Bryce.
什么 谁告诉你的 没有 我并没有这个打算
What? who told you that? no, i'm not.
有人看见你今早拿了一大叠钱
Someone saw you with a wad of cash this morning.
你有多少钱 不关你的事
- how much do you have? - it's none of your business.
而且我也不会竞标 我已经不喜欢他了
And i'm not bidding, okay? i don't even like him anymore.
少来了
Oh, that'll be the day.
是真的 你请吧 把钱浪费在他身上 我不在乎
It's true. go ahead, waste your money on him. i don't care.
现在让我们热烈欢迎
And now, will you all give a big mayfield school welcome...
1963年的篮子男孩
...to your 1963 basketboys.
我可以说我什么都不在乎
I could say I didn't care all I wanted...
但是看到布莱斯 西装革履的走出来
...but seeing Bryce walk out in his jacket and tie...
手里拎着他的餐篮
...holding that picnic basket...
我的头又开始晕眩了
...set my head spinning again.
15元一次
Fifteen going once.
- 拍卖会过得飞快 - 15元两次
- The auction seemed to fly by. - fifteen going twice.
梅西泰勒 15元中标
Sold to macy taylor for $15.
转眼间 就到了 艾迪楚拉克
Before i knew it, Eddie Trulock was called.
八号 是艾迪楚拉克
Number eight is Eddie Trulock.
意味着 下一个 就是布莱斯
Which meant Bryce was next.
艾迪是辩论队队员
Eddie is a member of the debate team.
他的爱好有钓鱼
And his hobbies include fishing...
组装航模
...and model-airplane building.
谁愿意出价5元
Who will give me $5?
- 为什么没人出价 他很好呀 - 就是呀
- why isn't anyone bidding? he's so nice. - exactly.
没人吗
Nobody?
8元
Eight dollars.
茱莉贝克8元中标
Sold to Juli Baker for $8.
怎么会这样
How did this happen?
是因为 我同情艾迪吗
Was it because i felt bad for Eddie?
还是因为 我不相信我自己能忍住不去竞标布莱斯
Or was it because i couldn't trust myself with Bryce?
在去多媒体教室的路上
As i made my way to the multi-purpose room...
我思考着突变的事态
...i contemplated the startling turn of events.
我即将 和艾迪楚拉克 共进午餐
Here i was, about to have lunch with Eddie Trulock...
而我想了大半个人生的男孩
...while the boy i mooned over for half my life...
却将要和我的死敌共进午餐
...was going to share a meal with my mortal enemy.
我想要谢谢你 对我出价
I wanna thank you for bidding on me.
我真的很感动
It was touch-and-go there for a while.
不 我是真心的 我觉得挺有趣的
No, i wanted to. this will be fun.
- 我听说 你喜欢 组建航模 - 对啊
- i hear you like building model airplanes. - yeah.
我和我爸爸刚刚完成一架
My father and i just finished a
俄国米格19 1955年产的
russian mig-19. it was made in 1955.
米格的第一架超音速战斗机
Mig's first supersonic fighter.
很难弄 因为驾驶舱是凹进去的
tricky because the cockpit was recessed
我试着全神贯注在艾迪身上
I tried to give Eddie my full attention.
但 很难 因为布莱斯就在他身后
But it was difficult, because Bryce was right behind him.
艾迪在说什么进气阀
Eddie was saying something about intake valves...
布莱斯突然站起来了
...when out of nowhere, Bryce stood
并向我大步走了过来
up and marched straight towards me.
茱莉 我有话对你说
Hey, Juli, i gotta talk to you.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
他要吻我 吻我
He was going to kiss me. to kiss me.
我这辈子都在等的那个吻
All my life i've been waiting for that kiss.
但不是这样的 不是这样
But not like this. not this way.
我拼命骑着单车回到家 我想我的肺都快气炸了
I pedaled home so hard, i thought my lungs would burst.
茱莉安娜
Julianna?
Julianna.
宝贝
Honey?
怎么了
What's wrong?
我不能说
I can't.
宝贝
Sweetheart...
你可以跟我说说
...you can tell me.
布莱斯想吻我
Bryce tried to kiss me.
是吗
He did?
在学校
In school.
当着大家的面
In front of everybody.
妈妈 请不要开门
Mom, please don't get it.
有可能是他
It's probably him.
宝贝
Sweetheart...
也许你应该跟他谈谈
...maybe you should talk to him.
我不行
I can't.
布莱斯不肯放过我
Bryce wouldn't leave me alone.
他不断地打我家电话
He kept calling on the phone.
敲我家门
And knocking on the door.
甚至偷偷绕过来 敲我的窗
He even snuck around the house and tapped on my window.
茱莉 求求你 让我见见你
Juli! please, i gotta see you!
出来吧 就一分钟
Come on out, just for a minute!
为什么他不明白
Why didn't he understand that i
我就想一个人静一静
just wanted to be left alone?
求求你
Please!
两天后 布莱斯停下来了
After two days, Bryce stopped.
我以为终于结束了
And i thought it was finally over.
然后 一天下午
Then, one afternoon, I was coming
我去前厅看书
into the front room to read
却听到院子里传来噪音
...when i heard a noise in the yard.
他在干嘛
Hey, what's he doing?
茱莉 冷静点 我允许他的
Juli, calm down. I gave him permission.
允许 允许什么 他在挖洞诶
Permission? permission for what? he's digging a hole.
我告诉他可以的
I told him he could.
为什么
But why?
我告诉他可以挖的
I told him he could.
看着他挖我的草地 真的是一种折磨
It was torture seeing him dig up my grass.
我爸为什么会允许他做这个
How could my father let him do this?
布莱斯知道我也在家
Bryce knew i was there too.
他走了
He's gone.
一棵树
A tree?
他要种一棵树
He's planting a tree?
那是
Is it a?
我根本不需要问
I didn't really need to ask.
我从树叶的形状和
I could tell from the shape of the leaves...
树干的质地就能分辨
...and the texture of the trunk.
那是无花果树
It was a sycamore tree.
当她从走出大门 我回想起
When she walked out of the door, I thought
第一次见到她
back to the first time I saw her
怎么会有人
How could anybody, ever, have
想要逃离 茱莉贝克呢
wanted to run away from Juli Baker?
他用那双眼睛看着我
He looked at me with those eyes.
那双再次发光的双眼
Those once again dazzling eyes.
我知道 我的初吻
And I knew that Bryce Loski was still
还会留给布莱斯 洛斯基
walking around with my first kiss
但不会太久的
But he wouldn't be for long.
我们站在那里 我才发现 这么多年来
As we stood there, I realized that all these years...
我们从来没有真的聊过
...we never really talked.
你需要帮忙吗
Do you need some help?
好呀
Yeah.
但是那一天 我们开始聊天了
But that day, we started.
我知道我们会聊很久的
And i knew we'd be talking for a long time.
欢迎关注微信公众号
搜索  o_meiju
或微博 @ Orange字幕组
Orange 字幕组
更多精彩请访问 www.orangesub.com